Okay. Hi, everyone. Um, so let's get started again today.
好的。嗨，大家好。嗯，让我们今天再次开始吧。
So today's lecture what I'm going to do,
那么今天的讲座我要做什么，
is be talking about, um,
是在谈论，嗯，
question answering over text.
回答文本的问题。
Um, this is another of the big successes
嗯，这是另一个重大成功
in using deep learning inside natural language processing,
在自然语言处理中使用深度学习，
and it's also a technology that has some really obvious commercial uses.
它也是一种具有一些非常明显的商业用途的技术。
So it's an, it's an area that has attracted
所以这是一个吸引人的领域
a lot of attention in the last couple of years.
在过去几年中备受关注。
So this is the overall plan.
所以这是整体计划。
Um, just a couple of reminders and things at the beginning about final project stuff,
嗯，刚开始时关于最终项目的一些提醒和事情，
and then we'll, basically all of it is talking about question-answering starting with, um,
然后我们基本上所有这些都是在谈论问答，首先，嗯，
motivation history, um, talking about the SQuAD data,
动机历史，嗯，谈论SQuAD数据，
uh, a particular simple model, our Stanford Attentive Reader.
呃，一个特别简单的模型，我们的Stanford Attentive Reader。
Then talking about some other more complex,
然后谈论其他一些更复杂的，
um, stuff into the most modern stuff.
嗯，进入最现代化的东西。
Um, yeah, so in a census, um,
嗯，是的，所以在人口普查中，嗯，
lecture serves a double purpose because if you're going to do the,
讲座有双重目的，因为如果你要去做，
the default final project, well,
默认的最终项目，嗯，
it's about textual question-answering,
这是关于文本问答，
and this is your chance to learn something about the area of textual question-answering,
这是你学习文本问答领域的机会，
and the kinds of models you might want to be thinking about and building.
以及您可能想要思考和构建的模型类型。
Um but the content of this lecture pretty much is in
嗯，但这个讲座的内容几乎就是
no way specifically tied to the default final project,
没有办法专门绑定默认的最终项目，
apart from by subject matter that really it's telling you about
除了它真正告诉你的主题之外
how people use neural nets to build question-answering systems.
人们如何使用神经网络建立问答系统。
Okay. So first just quickly on the reminders,
好的。所以首先快速提醒一下，
um, mid-quarter survey.
嗯，季度调查。
I mean, a huge number of people,
我的意思是，有很多人，
um, have actually filled this in already.
嗯，实际上已经填补了这个。
Uh, we already had over 60 percent, um, um,
呃，我们已经有超过60％，嗯，嗯，
filling-it-in rate by which by the standards of people
按人们的标准填写的加入率
who do surveys they come as a huge success already.
谁做了调查他们已经取得了巨大的成功。
But if you're not in that percent, um,
但如果你不是那个百分比，嗯，
we'd still love to have your feedback and now's the perfect time to do it.
我们仍然希望得到您的反馈，现在是完成它的最佳时机。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
I just wanted to sort of have a note on custom final projects.
我只想对自定义最终项目进行说明。
Um, so in general, um,
嗯，一般来说，嗯，
it's great to get feedback on custom final projects.
很高兴获得有关自定义最终项目的反馈。
There's a formal mechanism for that which is
这是一个正式的机制
the project proposal that I mentioned last time.
我上次提到的项目提案。
It's also great to chat to people,
和人聊天也很棒，
um, informally about, um, final projects.
嗯，非正式地说，嗯，最后的项目。
And so I'm one of those people and I have
所以我是那些人中的一员而且我拥有
been talking to lots of people about final projects,
一直在与很多人谈论最终项目，
and, uh, very happy to do so.
而且，呃，非常高兴这样做。
But there's sort of a problem that there's only one of me.
但有一个问题是我只有一个人。
Um, so I do also, um,
嗯，所以我也这样做，嗯，
encourage you to realize that among the various TAs that
鼓励你在各种TA之间意识到这一点
really lots of them have had experience of different deep learning projects,
他们中很多人都有过不同深度学习项目的经验，
and in particular on the office hours page,
特别是在办公时间页面，
there's a table that's like this but you can read it if you look at it on your own laptop,
有一张像这样的桌子，但是如果你在自己的笔记本电脑上看到它，你可以阅读它，
which talks about the experience of different TA's.
谈论不同TA的经验。
And many of them have experience in different areas,
他们中的许多人都有不同领域的经验，
and many of them are also good people to talk to about final projects.
他们中的许多人也是谈论最终项目的好人。
Okay. Um, so for the default final project, the textual question-answering.
好的。嗯，对于默认的最终项目，文本问答。
So um, draft materials for that app today,
那么，今天该应用程序的材料草案，
um, right now on the website actually.
嗯，现在在网站上。
Um, we're calling them draft because we think that there are still
嗯，我们称之为草案，因为我们认为还有
probably a few things that are gonna get changed over the next week,
可能有一些事情会在下周改变，
so um, don't regard as completely final in terms of the code that,
所以，在代码方面，不要认为完全是最终的，
you know, it's sort of 90 percent final.
你知道，这是90％的决赛。
So in terms of deciding whether you're going to do, um,
所以在决定你是否会这样做的时候，嗯，
a custom final project or a default final project,
自定义最终项目或默认最终项目，
and working out what you're putting into your project proposal.
并确定你在项目提案中的内容。
Um, it should be, you know,
嗯，它应该是，你知道，
well more than, um,
嗯，嗯，
what you need for this year.
你今年需要什么。
Okay. The one other, um,
好的。另一个，嗯，
final bit I just wanted to say that I didn't get to
最后一点我只想说我没有达到
last time is so for the final projects,
最后一次是最后的项目，
regardless of which kind you're doing,
不管你在做什么，
um, well, part of it is, um,
嗯，好吧，部分原因是，嗯，
doing some experiments, of
做一些实验
doing stuff with data and code,
做数据和代码的东西，
and getting some numbers and things like that.
并获得一些数字和类似的东西。
But I do really, um,
但我真的，嗯，
encourage people to also remember that an important part of
鼓励人们也记住这一重要部分
the final project is writing a final project report.
最后的项目是撰写最终的项目报告。
And this is no different to any research project of the kinds that,
这与任何类型的研究项目没有什么不同，
um, students do for conferences or journals and things like that, right?
嗯，学生们为会议或期刊以及类似的事情做的，对吗？
You spend months commonly working over your code and experiments.
您花费数月时间来处理代码和实验。
But in most cases,
但在大多数情况下，
the main evaluation of your work is from people reading,
你工作的主要评价来自人们阅读，
a written paper output version of things.
事物的书面纸输出版本。
So it's really important that,
所以非常重要的是，
that paper version sort of reflects the work
那纸质版本反映了这项工作
that you did and the interesting ideas that you came up with,
你做过的以及你想出的有趣想法，
and explains them well and present your experiments,
并解释它们并展示你的实验，
and all of those things.
以及所有这些事情。
And so we encourage you to sort of do a good job at writing up your projects.
因此，我们鼓励您在编写项目时做得很好。
Um, here is just sort of a vague outline of, you know,
嗯，这里只是一个模糊的轮廓，你知道，
what a typical project write-up is likely to look like.
典型的项目写作可能是什么样子。
Now, there isn't really one size completely fits all
现在，并没有一个尺寸完全适合所有人
because depending on what you've done different things might be appropriate.
因为取决于你做了什么，不同的事情可能是合适的。
But, you know, typically the first page,
但是，你知道，通常是第一页，
you'll have an abstract for the paper and the introduction to the paper.
你将有一篇论文的摘要和论文的介绍。
You'll spend some time talking about related prior work.
你会花一些时间谈论相关的先前工作。
Um, you'll talk about what kind of models you built for a while.
嗯，你会谈谈你建立了一段时间的模型。
Um, there's probably some discussion of what data you are using for your projects.
嗯，可能会讨论你正在为项目使用什么数据。
Um, experiments commonly with some tables and figures about the things that you're doing.
嗯，通常用一些关于你正在做的事情的表格和数字进行实验。
Um, more tables and figures talking about the results as to how well your systems work.
嗯，更多的表格和数字谈论你的系统运作良好的结果。
Um, it's great to have some error analysis to see
嗯，很高兴看到一些错误分析
what kind of things that you got right and wrong,
什么样的事情你是对是非，
and then maybe at the end there's sort of
然后也许最后会有一些
plans for the future, conclusions, or something like that.
计划未来，结论或类似的东西。
Okay. Um, that's sort of it for my extra administrative reminders.
好的。嗯，这就是我的额外行政提醒。
Um, are there any questions on final projects that people are dying to know?
嗯，对于人们最不知道的最终项目有什么问题吗？
[NOISE] Okay. Good luck.
[NOISE]好的。祝好运。
I just meant to say good luck.
我只想说祝你好运。
Yeah. Good luck with your final projects. [LAUGHTER] Okay.
是啊。祝你最后的项目好运。 [大笑]好的。
So now moving into,
所以现在进入，
um, yeah, the question answering.
嗯，是的，问题回答。
Okay. So, I mean- so question answering is
好的。所以，我的意思是 - 所以问题回答是
a very direct application for something that human beings,
一个人类非常直接的应用，
um, want to do.
嗯，想做。
Um, well, maybe human beings don't in general want to know this.
嗯，也许人类通常不想知道这一点。
Um, here's my query of "Who was Australia's third prime minister?".
嗯，这是我对“谁是澳大利亚第三任总理？”的质询。
Um, maybe, yeah, that's not really the kind of
嗯，也许，是的，那不是真的那种
thing you're gonna put into your queries but,
你要提出的问题但是，
you know, maybe you query,
你知道，也许你查询，
"Who was the lead singer of Big Thief?"
“谁是Big Thief的主唱？”
or something like that. I don't know.
或类似的东西。我不知道。
Um, you're, uh, but you know,
嗯，你，呃，但是你知道，
lots- a large percentage of stuff [NOISE] on the web
很多 - 网上很大比例的东西[噪音]
is that people actually are asking for answers to questions.
人们实际上是在寻求问题的答案。
And so, if I put in this query into Google,
所以，如果我将此查询添加到Google中，
it actually just works.
它实际上只是工作。
It tells me the answer is John Christian Watson.
它告诉我答案是John Christian Watson。
And, um, so that's sort of question answering working in the real world.
而且，嗯，所以这是回答在现实世界中工作的问题。
Um, if you try different kinds of questions in Google,
嗯，如果你在谷歌尝试不同类型的问题，
you'll find that some of them work and lots of them don't work.
你会发现其中一些是有效的，而且很多都不起作用。
And when they don't work,
当他们不工作时，
you're just sort of getting whatever kind of information retrieval, web search results.
你只是得到任何类型的信息检索，网络搜索结果。
Um, there is one fine point that I just wanted,
嗯，有一个我想要的好点，
um, to mention down here.
嗯，在这里提一下。
So another thing that Google has is the Google Knowledge Graph,
谷歌的另一件事是谷歌知识图，
which is a structured graph representation of knowledge.
这是知识的结构化图形表示。
And some kinds of questions,
还有一些问题，
um, being answered from that structured knowledge representation.
嗯，从结构化的知识表示中得到回答。
And so, I mean,
所以，我的意思是，
quite a lot of the time for things like movies,
很多时候像电影这样的东西，
it's coming from that structured graph.
它来自那个结构化的图形。
If you're sort of saying, "Who's the director of a movie?"
如果你有点说，“谁是电影导演？”
or something like that.
或类似的东西。
But this answer isn't coming from that.
但这个答案并非来自于此。
This answer is a genuine,
这个答案是真的，
the kind of stuff we're gonna talk about today.
我们今天要讨论的那种东西。
It's textual question answering from a web page where
这是从网页上回答的文字问题
Google's question and answering system has
谷歌的问答系统有
extracted the answer and is sticking it up there.
提取答案并坚持到那里。
Um, if you're, um,
嗯，如果你是，嗯，
wanting to explore these things, um,
想要探索这些东西，嗯，
if you get one of these boxes sort of down here where I've cut it off,
如果你把这些盒子中的一个放在这里，我把它切掉了，
there's a little bit of gray that says,
有一点灰色说，
"How did I get this result?".
“我是怎么得到这个结果的？”
And if you click on that,
如果你点击它，
it actually tells you what source it's getting it from and you can see if it's doing it
它实际上告诉你它是从哪个来源得到的，你可以看看它是否正在这样做
from the textual question answering system or from something like the Knowledge Graph.
来自文本问答系统或知识图。
Okay. Um, so the- in general,
好的。嗯，所以 - 一般来说，
the motivation for question answering is that these days there's
问答的动机是这些日子
just these sort of massive collections of full text documents,
只是这些大量的全文文档集，
i.e., there's the web.
即，有网络。
Um, so that there are sort of billions of documents of information.
嗯，所以有数十亿的信息文件。
And traditionally, when people first started
传统上，当人们第一次开始时
thinking about search information retrieval as a field,
将搜索信息检索视为一个领域，
you know, nothing of that kind of quantity and size existed, right?
你知道，这种数量和大小都不存在，对吧？
That when people first started building search systems,
当人们第一次开始构建搜索系统时，
it was sort of unthinkable to index
索引是不可想象的
whole documents because no one had hard disks big enough in those days, right?
整个文件，因为当时没有人有足够大的硬盘，对吧？
That really- they were indexing titles or titles and abstracts or something like that.
真的 - 他们正在索引标题或标题和摘要或类似的东西。
And so, it seemed perfectly adequate in those days to say, "Okay.
因此，在那些日子里，说“好吧。
We're just gonna send you- give you your results."
我们只是要发给你 - 给你结果。“
as to "Here's a list of documents."
关于“这是一份文件清单”。
because the documents are only a hundred words long.
因为这些文件只有一百多字。
But that's clearly not the case now when we have the sort of, you know,
但是，当我们有这种情况时，情况显然不是这样，你知道，
ten minute read, Medium posts um, which might have the answer to a question.
十分钟阅读，中等帖子，这可能有一个问题的答案。
And so, there's this need to sort of say, "Well,
所以，有必要说，“嗯，
can we just have systems that will give us answers to questions?".
我们能否拥有能够为我们提供问题答案的系统？“
And a lot of the recent changes in technology have hugely underlined that need.
最近很多技术变化都强调了这种需求。
So, returning documents works okay if you're sitting at your laptop,
所以，如果你坐在你的笔记本电脑上，退回的文件也可以，
but it works really terribly if you're on your phone and it works even more
但如果你在手机上它的工作原理会更加有效，那么它的工作非常糟糕
terribly if you're trying to work with speech on a digital assistant device,
非常糟糕的是，如果你想在数字助理设备上使用语音，
something like an Alexa system.
像Alexa系统的东西。
And so, we really want to actually be able to produce
所以，我们真的希望能够生产出来
systems that can give the answers to people's questions.
能够回答人们问题的系统。
And so typically, doing that is factored into two parts.
通常情况下，这样做会分为两部分。
That the first part of that is we still do information retrieval.
第一部分是我们仍在进行信息检索。
We use stand- normally quite standard information retrieval techniques to
我们使用通常非常标准的信息检索技术
find documents that quite likely to con- maintain- contain an answer.
找到很可能包含答案的文件。
And the reason that this is normally done by quite traditional techniques is because
而这通常是通过相当传统的技术来完成的原因是因为
the traditional techniques are extremely scalable over billions of documents,
传统技术在数十亿文档上具有极高的可扩展性，
whereas current neural systems actually
而实际的当前神经系统
aren't really scalable over billions of documents.
并不是真正可扩展到数十亿个文档。
But that's an area in sort of which research is ongoing.
但这是一个正在进行研究的领域。
But then once we have sort of some candidate likely documents,
但是，一旦我们有一些候选人可能的文件，
we want to find, uh,
我们想找到，呃，
do they contain an answer,
他们是否包含答案，
and if so, what is the answer?
如果是的话，答案是什么？
And so at that point,
所以在这一点上，
we have a document or a paragraph,
我们有一个文件或段落，
and we're saying, "Can we answer this question from there?"
我们说，“我们可以从那里回答这个问题吗？”
And then that problem is often referred to as the Reading Comprehension problem.
然后，这个问题通常被称为阅读理解问题。
And so that's really what I'm gonna focus on today.
所以这就是我今天要关注的事情。
Um, Reading Comprehension isn't a new problem.
嗯，阅读理解不是一个新问题。
I mean it- you can trace it back into the early days of artificial intelligence and NLP.
我的意思是 - 你可以追溯到人工智能和NLP的早期阶段。
So, back in the 70's,
所以，早在70年代，
a lot of NLP work was trying to do Reading Comprehension.
很多NLP工作都试图做阅读理解。
I mean one of the famous strands of that, um, was, um,
我的意思是其中一个着名的股，嗯，是，嗯，
Sir Roger Shank was a famous,
Roger Shank爵士是着名的，
um, early NLP person.
嗯，早期的NLP人。
Though not a terribly nice man.
虽然不是一个非常好的男人。
I don't think, actually.
实际上，我不这么认为。
Um, but the Yale School of AI was a very well-known,
嗯，但耶鲁大学的人工智能学校是一个非常有名的，
um, NLP approach and really,
嗯，NLP方法真的，
it was very focused on Reading Comprehension.
它非常注重阅读理解。
Um, but it's sort of,
嗯，但是有点像，
you know, I think it was sort of the time, it was too early in any way.
你知道，我认为这有点时间，任何方式都太早了。
It sort of died out. Nothing much came out of that.
它有点死了。没有太多的东西出来。
Um, but then in- right just before the turn of the mil- millennium,
嗯，但接下来就在千禧年之前，
Lynette Hirschman revived this idea and said, "Well,
Lynette Hirschman恢复了这个想法并说：“好吧，
maybe a good challenge would be to find the kind of
也许一个很好的挑战就是找到那种
Reading Comprehension questions that elementary school kids do,
阅读小学生做的理解问题，
and let's see if we could get,
让我们看看我们能否得到，
um, computers to do that.
嗯，计算机就是这样做的。
And some people tried that with fairly simple methods,
有些人用相当简单的方法尝试过，
which only work mediocrely.
这只是平庸的工作。
Then sort of somewhat after that, um,
那之后有点，嗯，
Chris Burges who was a guy who was at
克里斯伯格斯谁是一个人在
Microsoft Research and he wasn't really an NLP person at all.
微软研究院，他根本不是一个NLP人。
He was a machine learning person,
他是一个机器学习者，
but he got it into his head, um,
但他把它放到他的头上，嗯，
that while really a big problem that should be being worked on is
虽然真正应该解决的一个大问题是
Machine Comprehension and he suggested that you sort of could codify it like this.
机器理解，他建议你可以像这样编纂它。
And this is a particular clean codification
这是一个特别干净的编纂
that has lived on and we'll look at more today.
已经存在，我们今天会看到更多。
All right. So, a machine comprehends a passage of text.
行。因此，一台机器理解了一段文字。
If there's any question regarding that text that can be
如果有任何关于该文本的问题可以
answered correctly by a majority of native speakers,
大多数母语人士正确回答，
that machine can provide a string,
那台机器可以提供一个字符串，
which those speakers would agree both answers
那些发言者会同意这两个答案
that question and does not contain information irrelevant to that question.
该问题并不包含与该问题无关的信息。
Um, and he sort of proposed this as sort of a challenge problem for
嗯，他有点认为这是一个挑战问题
artificial intelligence and set about collecting a corpus,
人工智能和着手收集语料库，
the MCTest corpus, which was meant to be a simple Reading Comprehension challenge.
MCTest语料库，这是一个简单的阅读理解挑战。
Um, so they collected, um,
嗯，所以他们收集了，嗯，
stories, um, which, um,
故事，嗯，哪，嗯，
were meant to be kids' stories, you know.
你知道，这些都是孩子们的故事。
"Alyssa got to the beach after a long trip.
“长途旅行后，艾莉莎到了海边。
She's from Charlotte. She traveled from Atlanta.
她来自夏洛特。她从亚特兰大旅行。
She's now in Miami".
她现在在迈阿密“。
Sort of pretty easy stuff.
很简单的东西。
And then there were questions.
然后有问题。
"Why did Alyssa go to Miami?"
“为什么Alyssa去了迈阿密？”
Um, and then the answer is,
嗯，然后答案是，
"To visit some friends".
“拜访一些朋友”。
And so you've got there this string that is coming from the passage.
所以你已经到了那条来自通道的字符串。
That's the answer to the question.
这就是问题的答案。
Um, so the MCTest is a corpus of
嗯，所以MCTest是一个语料库
about 600 such stories and that challenge existed, and a few people worked on it.
大约600个这样的故事和挑战存在，并且有一些人参与其中。
But that never really went very far either for the next couple of years.
但是在接下来的几年里，这种情况从未真正走得太远。
But what really changed things was that in 2015,
但真正改变的是2015年，
and then with more stuff in 2016,
然后在2016年有更多的东西，
um, deep learning people got interested in this idea of,
嗯，深入学习的人对这个想法感兴趣，
"Could we perhaps build neural question answering systems?"
“我们可能会建立神经问答系统吗？”
And it seemed like if you wanted to do that, um,
似乎你想要这样做，嗯，
something like MCTest could only be a test set
像MCTest这样的东西只能是一个测试集
and the ways to make progress would be to do what had been done
取得进展的方法是做所做的事情
in other domains and to actually build just- hand build a large training set of passages,
在其他领域并实际构建一个大型的训练集通道，
questions, and answers in such a way that would be able to train neural networks using
以能够训练神经网络的方式提出问题和答案
the kind of supervised learning techniques that we've
我们采用的监督学习技巧
concentrated on so far in this class.
到目前为止集中在这堂课上。
And indeed, the kind of supervised neural network learning techniques,
事实上，这种监督神经网络学习技术，
which is [NOISE] actually the successful stuff that
这是[NOISE]实际上是成功的东西
powers nearly all the applications of deep learning,
几乎所有深度学习的应用，
not only in NLP,
不仅在NLP，
but also in other fields like vision.
而且在视觉等其他领域。
Um, and so the first subs- the first such dataset was built by
嗯，所以第一个子 - 第一个这样的数据集是由
people at DeepMind over CNN and Daily Mail news stories.
DeepMind的人们通过美国有线电视新闻网和每日邮报新闻报道。
Um, but then the next year, um,
嗯，但接下来的第二年，嗯，
Pranav Rajpurkar is a Stanford PhD student
Pranav Rajpurkar是斯坦福大学博士生
working with Percy Liang and a couple of other students, um,
与Percy Liang和其他几个学生一起工作，嗯，
produced the SQuAD dataset,
制作了SQuAD数据集，
which was actually a much better designed dataset and proved to be
这实际上是一个设计得更好的数据集并且被证明是
sort of much more successful at driving this forward.
在推动这一进展方面取得更大的成功。
And then following along from that,
接下来，
other people started to produce lots of other,
其他人开始生产其他很多，
um, question answering datasets which, you know,
嗯，问题回答数据集，你知道，
many of them have interesting advantages
其中许多都有其有趣的优点
and disadvantages of their own including MS MARCO,
他们自己的缺点，包括MS MARCO，
TriviaQA, RACE, blah, blah, blah, lots of them.
TriviaQA，RACE，等等，等等，等等。
Um, but for today's class,
嗯，但对于今天的班级，
I'm gonna concentrate on SQuAD,
我会专注于SQUAD，
because SQuAD is actually the one that has been by far the most widely used.
因为SQuAD实际上是迄今为止使用最广泛的SQUAD。
And because it - it was just a well-constructed clean dataset,
因为它 - 它只是一个构造良好的干净数据集，
that it sort of just proved a profitable one for people to work with.
它有点被证明是一个有利可图的人与之合作。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Okay. Um, so, that was reading comprehension.
好的。嗯，这就是阅读理解。
I'll also just quickly tell you the, um,
我也会很快告诉你，嗯，
the history of open domain question answering.
开放域名问答的历史。
So, the difference here for the- the field of
所以，这里的区别是 - 的领域
Open-domain Question Answering that we're saying, okay,
我们说的开放域问题回答，好的，
there's an encyclopedia or there's a web crawl,
有一个百科全书或者有一个网络爬行，
I'm just going to ask a question,
我只是想问一个问题，
can you answer it?
你能回答吗？
So, it's this bigger task of question answering.
所以，这是一个更大的问题回答任务。
And, you know, that was something that again was thought about,
并且，你知道，这是一个被再次考虑的事情，
um, very early on.
嗯，非常早。
So, there's this kind of early, um,
所以，有这种早期，嗯，
CACM paper by Simmons who sort of explores how you could
西蒙斯的CACM论文，探讨了你的方法
do answering questions as textual question-answering, um, and yet, you know,
回答问题作为文本问答，嗯，但是，你知道，
he has the idea that what's going to
他知道会发生什么
happen is you're gonna dependency parse the question,
碰巧是你要依赖解析这个问题，
and dependency parse sentences of the text,
和依赖解​​析文本的句子，
and then sort of do tree matching over the dependency parses,
然后在依赖关系解析上进行树匹配，
um, to get out the answers.
嗯，得出答案。
And, you know, that's in some sense
而且，你知道，这在某种意义上说
actually prefigured work that people actually were then attempting to do 35 years later.
实际上是人们实际上在35年后尝试做的预示工作。
Um, getting a bit more modern, um, Julian Kupiec,
嗯，变得更现代，嗯，Julian Kupiec，
she was working at Xerox PARC at the time,
她当时在Xerox PARC工作，
um, came up with this system called MURAX,
嗯，想出了这个名为MURAX的系统，
and so at this stage in the 90s there started to be the first, um,
所以在90年代的这个阶段开始有第一个，嗯，
digitally available encyclopedias available,
数字可用的百科全书，
so he was using the Grolier's Encyclopedia,
所以他正在使用Grolier的百科全书，
and so he said about trying to build a system that could answer
所以他说试图建立一个可以回答的系统
questions over that encyclopedia using,
关于该百科全书使用的问题，
in general, fairly sort of shallow, um,
一般来说，相当浅，嗯，
linguistic processing methods, i.e, regular expressions.
语言处理方法，即正则表达式。
Um, for, after [LAUGHTER] having, um,
嗯，因为，在[笑声]之后，嗯，
done information retrieval search over that.
完成信息检索搜索。
But that started to evoke more interest from other people,
但这开始引起其他人的兴趣，
and so in 1999 the US National Institutes of Standards and Technology, um,
所以1999年美国国家标准与技术研究院，嗯，
instituted a TREC question-answering track where the idea was,
设立了一个TREC问答环节，其中的想法是，
there was a large collection of News-wire documents,
有大量的新闻线文件，
and you could be asked to provide the question of them,
你可能会被要求提供他们的问题，
and lots of people started to build question answering systems.
很多人开始建立问答系统。
Indeed, if in some sense that was
的确，如果从某种意义上说是这样的话
this competition which was where people at IBM started,
这场比赛是IBM人们开始的地方，
um, working on textual question-answering,
嗯，致力于文本问答，
and then, um, sort of a decade later, um,
然后，嗯，十年后，嗯，
IBM rejigged things into the sexier format of,
IBM将事物重新调整为更性感的格式，
um, let's build a Jeopardy contestant rather than let's answer questions from the news,
嗯，让我们建立一个Jeopardy选手，而不是让我们回答新闻中的问题，
and that then led to their DeepQA system in 2011.
然后在2011年导致了他们的DeepQA系统。
Which I presume quite a few of you saw,
我认为你看到了很多，
these people saw Jeopardy IBM?
这些人看到了Jeopardy IBM？
Yeah, some of you.
是的，有些人。
Okay. So, that they were able to successfully, um,
好的。所以，他们能够成功，嗯，
build a question answering system that could compete at Jeopardy, um, and win.
建立一个可以在Jeopardy，嗯和胜利中竞争的问答系统。
Um, and, you know, like a lot of these demonstrations of
嗯，而且，你知道，就像很多这些演示一样
technological success there are things you can quibble about the way it was set up,
技术上的成功有些东西你可以对它的设置方式嗤之以鼻，
um, that really the kind of computer just had
嗯，那真是那种电脑
a speed advantage versus the human beings that had to buzz in to answer the question.
速度优势与人类不得不热衷于回答这个问题。
But, you know, nevertheless, fundamentally,
但是，你知道，从根本上说，
the textual question-answering had to work,
文本问答必须起作用，
that this was a system that was answering questions mainly based on textual passages,
这是一个主要基于文本段落回答问题的系统，
and it had to be able to find the answers to those questions correctly,
它必须能够正确找到这些问题的答案，
for the system to work.
使系统工作。
Um, so then, more recently again, um,
嗯，那么，最近又一次，嗯，
and really the first piece of work that did this with a neural system was,
并且真正用神经系统做的第一件工作是，
um, work that was, um,
嗯，那是工作，嗯，
done by a Stanford PhD student,
由斯坦福大学博士生完成，
that I'll get to later,
我以后会到的，
was then the idea of well,
那么好的想法，
could we replace traditional complex question answering systems
我们能否取代传统的复杂问答系统
by using a neural reading comprehension system,
通过使用神经阅读理解系统，
and that's proved to be very successful.
事实证明这是非常成功的。
So, to, to explain that a little bit more, um,
所以，要解释一下，嗯，
if you look at the kind of systems that were built for TREC question-answering,
如果你看一下那些为TREC问答而建的系统，
um, they were very complex multi-part systems.
嗯，它们是非常复杂的多部分系统。
And really, if you then look at something like,
真的，如果你再看看像，
IBM's Deep QA system it was sort of like this
IBM的Deep QA系统有点像这样
times 10 because it both had very complex systems like this,
10倍，因为它们都有非常复杂的系统，
but it ensembled together sort of six different components in every place,
但它在每个地方都有六种不同的组件，
and then did sort of,
然后做了一些，
um, classify a combination on top of them.
嗯，在它们之上对组合进行分类。
But so far, the current-.
但到目前为止，目前 - 。
This is sort of around a sort of a 2003 question answering system,
这类似于2003年的问答系统，
and so the kind of things that went through is,
所以经历的事情是，
so when there was a question,
所以当有问题时，
it parsed the question with a parser
它用解析器解析了这个问题
kind of like the ones we saw with our dependency parsers.
有点像我们用依赖解析器看到的那些。
It did some sort of
它做了某种
handwritten semantic normalization rules to try and get them into a better semantic form.
手写的语义规范化规则，试图让它们变成更好的语义形式。
It then had a question type classifier which tried to
然后它有一个问题类型分类器试图
work out what kind of semantic type is this question looking for,
找出这个问题寻找什么样的语义类型，
is it looking for a person name,
它在寻找一个人的名字，
or a country name,
或国名，
or a temperature, or something like that.
或温度，或类似的东西。
Um, it would, um, then, um,
恩，嗯，那么，嗯，
have an information retrieval system out of the document collection,
有一个文件集之外的信息检索系统，
um, which would find paragraphs that were likely to contain the answers.
嗯，会找到可能包含答案的段落。
Um, and then it would have a method of ranking
嗯，然后它会有一个排名的方法
those paragraph choices to see which ones are likely to have the answers.
那些段落选择，看看哪些可能有答案。
Um, it would then,
嗯，那么，
um, over there somewhere, um,
嗯，那边的某个地方，嗯，
run Named Entity Recognition on those passages to find entities that were in them.
在这些段落上运行命名实体识别以查找其中的实体。
These systems depended strongly on the use of
这些系统强烈依赖于使用
fine matching entities because then it could look for
精细匹配实体，因为它可以寻找
an entity which corresponded to the question type.
对应于问题类型的实体。
Um, then once it had candidate entities,
嗯，那么一旦它有候选实体，
it had to actually try and determine whether
它必须实际尝试并确定是否
these entities did or didn't answer the question.
这些实体确实或没有回答这个问题。
So, these people, this is the system from LCC by,
所以，这些人，这是来自LCC的系统，
um, Sanda Harabagiu and Dan Moldovan.
嗯，Sanda Harabagiu和Dan Moldovan。
They actually had some quite interesting stuff here,
他们实际上有一些非常有趣的东西，
where they had a kind of a loose theorem prover that would try and prove that, um,
他们有一种松散的定理证明，试图证明，嗯，
the semantic form of a piece of text,
一段文字的语义形式，
um, gave an answer to what the question was.
嗯，回答了问题所在。
So, you know, that was kind of cool stuff with an Axiomatic Knowledge Base,
所以，你知道，这是一个很酷的东西与Axiomatic知识库，
um, and eventually out would come an answer.
嗯，最终会出来答案。
Um, so, you know, something that is,
嗯，所以，你知道的，是的，
I do just want to emphasize, you know,
我只是想强调，你知道，
sometimes with these deep learning courses you get these days,
有时这些天你会得到这些深度学习课程，
the impression you have is that absolutely nothing worked before 2014,
你的印象是2014年之前绝对没有用，
uh, when we got back to deep learning,
呃，当我们回到深度学习时，
and that's not actually true.
而事实并非如此。
So, these kind of factoid question on,
所以，这类事实问题，
these kind of question answering systems within
这些问题的回答系统
a certain domain actually really worked rather well.
某个领域实际上真的很有效。
Um, so, I started saying the word Factoid Question Answering,
嗯，所以，我开始说“Factoid Question Answering”这个词，
and so let me explain that because that's the secret.
所以让我解释一下，因为这是秘密。
So, people, at least in NLP,
所以，人们，至少在NLP，
use the term "Factoid Question Answering" to mean
使用术语“Factoid Question Answering”来表示
the case that your answer is a named entity.
您的答案是命名实体的情况。
So, it's sort of something like, you know,
所以，它有点像，你知道，
what year was Elvis Presley born,
埃尔维斯普雷斯利出生于哪一年，
or what is the name of Beyonce's husband, or, um,
或者Beyonce的丈夫是什么名字，或者，嗯，
you know, which state,
你知道，哪个州，
um, has the most pork or something, I don't know.
嗯，有最多的猪肉什么的，我不知道。
Right, anything that's got,
对，任何有的东西，
anything that's sort of the answer is sort of some clear semantic type entity,
任何类似答案的东西都是一些清晰的语义类型实体，
and that's your answer.
那是你的答案。
I mean, so, within the space of those kind of questions,
我的意思是，在这类问题的空间内，
which actually is a significant part of the questions you get in web search, right?
这实际上是你在网络搜索中遇到的重要问题，对吗？
Lots of web search is just, you know,
你知道，很多网络搜索都是
who was the star of this movie,
谁是这部电影的明星，
or what year was somebody born, right?
或者哪一年出生，对吗？
There's zillions of those all the time.
那里有数以万计的人。
These systems actually really did work quite well
这些系统确实非常有效
that they could get about 70 percent of those questions right,
他们可以得到大约70％的问题，
um, which wasn't bad at all, um,
嗯，这一点都不差，嗯，
though that they really sort of didn't really
虽然他们真的不是真的
extend it out to other kinds of stuff beyond that.
将其扩展到其他类型的东西。
But whatever virtues they had, um,
但无论他们有什么美德，嗯，
they were extremely complex systems that people spent years put togeth- putting together,
他们是非常复杂的系统，人们花了多年的时间把它放在一起，
which had many components with a huge amount of hand-built stuff.
它有很多组件，手工制作的东西很多。
And most of the stuff was sort of built quite separately and tied together,
而且大多数东西都是完全独立构建并捆绑在一起的，
and you just sort of hope that it worked,
而你只是希望它有效，
um, well, when put together in composite.
嗯，好吧，当复合在一起时。
And so we can contrast that to what we then see later,
所以我们可以将其与我们后面看到的相对照，
um, for neural network-style systems.
嗯，对于神经网络式系统。
Okay. Um, so let me now say some more stuff about, um,
好的。嗯，现在让我说一些关于的东西，嗯，
the Stanford Question Answering Dataset or SQuAD that I just mentioned a little bit ago,
我刚才提到的Stanford Question Answering Dataset或SQuAD，
and as this is the data for the default final project as well.
因为这也是默认最终项目的数据。
Um, so what SQuAD has is,
嗯，那么SQUAD是什么，
questions in SQuAD have a passage,
SQUAD中的问题有一个段落，
which is a paragraph from Wikipedia.
这是维基百科的一段。
And then there is a question,
然后有一个问题，
here it's, "Which team won Super Bowl 50?"
在这里，“哪支球队赢得了超级碗50？”
And the goal of the system is to come up with the answer to this question.
该系统的目标是提出这个问题的答案。
Um, human reading comprehension.
嗯，人类的阅读理解力。
What is the answer to the question?
这个问题的答案是什么？
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Broncos.
野马。
Broncos. [LAUGHTER] Okay.
野马。 [大笑]好的。
Yeah. Um, so that's the answer to the question.
是啊。嗯，这就是问题的答案。
Um, and so by construction for SQuAD,
嗯，通过施工SQUAD，
the answer to a question is always a sub-sequence of words from the passage which is,
一个问题的答案总是来自该段落的一系列单词序列，
normally, it ends up being referred to as a span,
通常，它最终被称为跨度，
a sub-sequence of words from the passage.
文章的一个子序列。
So that's the only kind of questions you can have.
所以这是你唯一可以提出的问题。
You can't have questions that are counting questions,
你不能有问题，
or yes, no questions, or anything like that.
或是，没有问题，或类似的东西。
You can just pick out a sub-sequence.
你可以选择一个子序列。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
But, um, so they created in the first version about 100,000 examples.
但是，嗯，所以他们在第一个版本中创建了大约100,000个例子。
So there are a bunch of questions about each passage.
因此每个段落都有很多问题。
So it's sort of something like, um,
所以它有点像，嗯，
I think it's maybe sort of about five questions per passage,
我认为每篇文章可能有五个问题，
and there are 20,000 different bits that Wikipedia uses, used.
维基百科使用，使用了20,000个不同的位。
Um, and this sort of must be a span form,
嗯，这种必须是跨度形式，
as often referred to as extractive question answering.
通常被称为提取问题回答。
Okay. Um, here's just one more example
好的。嗯，这里只是另一个例子
that can give you some more sense of some of the things that are there,
这可以让你更多地了解一些存在的东西，
and it illustrates a couple of other factors.
它说明了其他几个因素。
Um, so, you know,
嗯，你知道，
even this one, I guess the previous one wasn't, um,
即便是这个，我想前一个不是，嗯，
completely obvious what your answers should be because
完全明显你的答案应该是什么，因为
maybe you could say the answer should just have been Broncos,
也许你可以说答案应该是野​​马队，
or you could have said it was Denver Broncos.
或者你可以说这是丹佛野马队。
Um, and in general,
嗯，总的来说，
even if you're answering with a span,
即使你正在回答，
there's gonna be variation as to how long a span you choose.
关于你选择的跨度多长时间会有变化。
Um, so what they did, um,
嗯，他们做了什么，嗯，
and so this was done with, on Mechanical Turk,
所以这是在Mechanical Turk上完成的，
gathering the data, or building questions,
收集数据或构建问题，
and getting answers, is that they got answers from three different people.
得到答案的是，他们得到了三个不同的人的答案。
So here's this question,
所以这是这个问题，
"Along with non-governmental and non-state schools,
“与非政府和非公立学校一起，
what is another name for private schools?"
私立学校的另一个名字是什么？“
And three human beings were asked the answer based on this passage.
根据这段经文，三个人被问到了答案。
And one said independent,
一个说独立，
and two said independent schools.
还有两所独立学校。
Um, this one, all three people gave the same answer.
嗯，这一个，所有三个人给出了相同的答案。
This one, again, you get two different answers,
这一次，你得到两个不同的答案，
so that they sample three answers.
这样他们就可以得到三个答案。
And basically, then, you can be correct if you're going with any of the answers.
基本上，如果你正在使用任何答案，那么你可以是正确的。
And so that sort of at least gives you a bit of robustness to variation in human answers.
因此，至少可以让你对人类答案的变化有一点强大感。
Okay. And that starts me into the topic of evaluation.
好的。这让我开始进入评估主题。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
And these slides here are entitled
这些幻灯片有权获得
SQuAD version 1,1 because that means in five minutes time,
SQuAD 1,1版，因为这意味着在五分钟的时间内，
I'm gonna tell you about SQuAD version 2,
我要告诉你有关SQuAD版本2的信息，
which adds a bit more stuff into it,
这会增加更多的东西，
but we'll just get 1,1 straight first.
但我们先得到1,1。
All right. So there are three answers that col- were collected.
行。因此收集了三个答案。
And so for evaluation metrics,
对于评估指标，
they suggested two evaluation metrics.
他们建议了两个评估指标。
The first one is exact match.
第一个是完全匹配。
So you're going to return a span.
所以你要返回一个跨度。
If the span is one of these three,
如果跨度是这三个中的一个，
you get one point,
你得到一分，
and if the scan,
如果扫描，
span is not one of these three,
跨度不是这三者中的一个，
you get zero for that question.
你得到的问题为零。
And then your accuracy is just the percent correct,
然后你的准确性只是正确的百分比，
so that's extremely simple.
所以这非常简单。
But the second metric, and actually,
但第二个指标，实际上，
the one that was favored as the primary metric,
作为主要指标的人，
was an F1 metric.
是一个F1指标。
So what you do for this F1 metric
那么你为这个F1指标做了什么
is you're matching at the word level for the different answers.
你是否在单词级别匹配不同的答案。
So you've treat each,
所以你要对待每一个，
you treat the system span and each gold answer as a bag of words,
你将系统范围和每个黄金答案视为一包文字，
and then you work out a precision, which is,
然后你计算出一个精度，
um, the percent of words in the system's answer that are actually in a span,
嗯，系统答案中的单词百分比实际上是跨度，
i- in a gold span, the recall,
我在黄金时段召回，
which is the percent of words in a gold span that are in the system's span.
这是系统跨度中黄金跨度中单词的百分比。
And then you calculate the harmonic mean of those two numbers
然后计算这两个数的调和平均值
and the harmonic mean is sort of a very conservative average.
调和均值是一种非常保守的平均值。
So it's close to the mean of those two numbers,
所以它接近这两个数字的平均值，
and that gives you a score.
这会给你一个分数。
And what you then do is, for each question,
那么你接下来要做的是，对于每个问题，
you'd return, you say its score is
你回来了，你说它的得分是
the maximum F1 over the three different answers that were collected from human beings.
从人类收集的三个不同答案中的最大F1。
And then for the whole, um, dataset,
然后对整个，嗯，数据集，
you then average those F1 scores across questions and that's then your final F1 result.
然后你可以在问题中平均那些F1得分，那就是你的最终F1成绩。
So that's a more complicated thing to say.
所以这是一个更复杂的事情。
Um, and we provide there sort of a val code,
嗯，我们提供那种val代码，
um, for you that does that.
嗯，对你这样做。
Um, but it sort of seems that F1 is actually
嗯，但实际上看起来有点像F1
a more reliable and better measure because if you use exact match,
一个更可靠和更好的措施，因为如果你使用完全匹配，
you know, even though there's of,
你知道，即使有，
a bit of robustness that comes on three people's answers,
三个人的答案有点强健，
three is not a very large sample,
三个不是很大的样本，
so there's sort of a bit of guessing as to whether you get
所以有一点猜测你是否得到了
exactly the same span some human being got,
一些人得到的完全相同的范围，
whereas you're sort of going to get a reasonable score
而你有点得到一个合理的分数
in the F1 even if your boundaries are off by a little.
在F1中，即使你的界限有点​​偏差。
So the F1 metric sort of, um,
那么F1指标，嗯，
is more reliable and avoids various kinds of artifacts as to how big
更可靠，避免各种各样的文物
or small an answer human beings tend to choose in some circumstances.
或者在某些情况下人类倾向于选择的答案。
Um, and so that's sort of being used as
嗯，所以这被用作
the primary metric that people score people on in the leader boards.
人们在排行榜中为人们评分的主要指标。
Um, final detail, both metrics, um,
嗯，最后的细节，两个指标，嗯，
ignore punctuation and the English articles a, an, the.
忽略标点符号和英文文章a，an，the。
Okay. Um, so how did things work out?
好的。嗯，那怎么办呢？
Um, so for SQuAD version 1,1, um.
嗯，对于SQuAD 1,1版，嗯。
A long time ago,
很久以前，
at the end of 2016,
在2016年底，
um, this is how the leaderboard looked.
嗯，这就是排行榜的样子。
Um, this is the bottom of the leaderboard at this point in
嗯，这是此时排行榜的底部
time because that allows me to show you a couple of things.
时间，因为这可以让我向你展示一些事情。
So down at the bottom of the leaderboard, um,
所以在排行榜的底部，嗯，
so they tested how well human beings did, um,
所以他们测试了人类的表现，嗯，
at answering these questions because you know,
回答这些问题，因为你知道，
human beings aren't perfect at answering questions either.
人类也不善于回答问题。
Um, and so the human performance that they measured,
嗯，他们测量的人的表现，
um, had an F1 score of 91,2.
嗯，得分为91,2。
And I'll come back to that again in a minute.
我会在一分钟后再回到那里。
Um, and so when they built the dataset,
嗯，当他们建立数据集时，
they built a logistic regression baseline which was sort of a conventional NLP system.
他们建立了一个逻辑回归基线，这是一种传统的NLP系统。
So, they dependency parsed the question and sentences of the answer.
因此，他们依赖解析问题和答案的句子。
They looked for dependency.
他们寻找依赖。
So dependency link matches,
所以依赖链接匹配，
so a word at both ends with the dependency relation in
所以两端的一个词都有依赖关系
between and count and matches of those and sort of pointing to a likely answer.
之间的计数和匹配，以及指向可能的答案。
Um, so as sort of a fairly competently built traditional NLP system of it's
嗯，所以它是一个相当完善的传统NLP系统
not as complex as but it's sort of in
没有那么复杂，但它有点像
the same vein of that early question answering system I mentioned.
与我提到的那个早期问答系统的脉络相同。
And it got an F1 of about 51.
它有一个大约51的F1。
So not hopeless, um,
所以不是没有希望，嗯，
but not that great compared to human beings.
但与人类相比并不是那么伟大。
And so, very shortly after that, um,
所以，在那之后不久，嗯，
people then started building
然后人们开始建设
neural network systems to try and do better at this task on this dataset.
神经网络系统尝试在此数据集上完成此任务。
And so, one of the first people to do this quite successfully,
所以，第一批成功完成这项工作的人之一，
um, were these people from Singapore Management University,
嗯，这些人来自新加坡管理大学，
maybe not the first place you would have thought of but, um,
也许不是你想到的第一个地方，但是，嗯，
they were really sort of the first people who showed that, yes,
他们真的是第一批表现出来的人，是的，
you could build an end-to-end trained neural network
你可以建立一个端到端训练的神经网络
for this task and do rather better.
为了完成这项任务而且做得更好。
And so, they got up to 67 F1.
所以，他们达到了67 F1。
Um, and well, then they had a second system.
嗯，那么他们有第二个系统。
They got 70 and then things started,
他们得到70然后开始了，
um, to, um, go on.
嗯，对，嗯，继续。
So that even by,
即便如此，
um, the end of 2016,
嗯，2016年底，
um, there started to be systems that really worked rather well on this task.
嗯，开始有这样的系统在这项任务上真的很有效。
Um, so here, this time was the,
嗯，所以这里，这次是，
um, top of the leaderboard.
嗯，排行榜的顶部。
So I'll talk later about this BiDAF system from, uh,
所以我稍后会谈到这个BiDAF系统，呃，
the AI to,
AI到，
Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence and the University of Washington.
艾伦人工智能研究所和华盛顿大学。
So, it was getting to 77 as
所以，它达到了77
a single system that like in just about all machine learning,
一个像几乎所有机器学习一样的系统，
people pretty soon noticed that if you made
人们很快就注意到，如果你做了
an ensemble of identically structured systems,
一系列结构相同的系统，
you could push the number higher and so if you ensemble those,
你可以把数字推得更高，所以如果你合奏那些，
you could then get another sort of whatever it is about four points
然后你可以得到另外一种关于四点的东西
and get up to 81, um, F1.
并且达到81，嗯，F1。
And so this was sort of around the situation when in the, uh, 2017, um,
所以这就像2017年的那种情况一样，嗯，
224N class, we first used SQuAD version one as jus- as a default final project.
224N类，我们首先使用SQuAD第一版作为jus-作为默认的最终项目。
And at that point, you know,
那时，你知道，
actually the best students got almost to the top of this leaderboard.
实际上，最好的学生几乎达到了这个排行榜的顶峰。
So our best, um,
所以我们最好的，嗯，
CS224N Final Project in winter 2017 made it into,
2017年冬季CS224N最终项目进入，
um, the equivalent of fourth place on this leaderboard,
嗯，相当于这个排行榜的第四名，
um, with 77,5 as their score.
嗯，得分为77,5。
So that was really rather cool.
所以这真的很酷。
Um, but that's a couple of years ago and since then,
嗯，但那是几年前和从那时起，
people have started building, um,
人们已经开始建设了，嗯，
bigger and bigger and more and more complex, um, systems.
越来越大，越来越复杂，嗯，系统。
And, um, so essentially,
而且，嗯，基本上，
you could sort of say that SQuAD version one is basically solved.
你可以说SQUAD第一版基本上已经解决了。
So the very best systems are now getting
所以最好的系统现在正在变得越来越好
F1 scores that are in the low 90s and in particular,
F1得分低于90，特别是
you can see that the best couple of, um,
你可以看到最好的一对，嗯，
systems have higher F1s and
系统有更高的F1和
well higher exact matches than what was measured for human beings.
比人类测量的精确匹配要高得多。
Uh, but like a lot of the claims of
呃，但是像很多人的说法一样
deep learning being better and performing from human being,
深度学习更好，表现更好，
than human beings, there's sort of some asterisks you can put after that.
比起人类，你可以在那之后添加一些星号。
I mean, in particular for this dataset,
我的意思是，特别是对于这个数据集，
the way they measured human performance was a little bit
他们衡量人类表现的方式有点儿
unfair because they only actually collected three human beings' answers.
不公平，因为他们实际上只收集了三个人的答案。
So, to judge, um, the human performance,
那么，判断，嗯，人类的表现，
the hu- those hu- each of those humans was being scored versus only two other humans.
hu-那些人 - 每个人都被评分而不是另外两个人。
And so, that means you only had two chances to match instead of three.
所以，这意味着你只有两次机会匹配而不是三次。
So, there's actually sort of a systematic underscoring of the human performance.
因此，实际上有一种系统性的强调人类表现。
But whatever, systems got very good at doing this.
但无论如何，系统都非常擅长这样做。
Um, so the next step, um,
嗯，下一步，嗯，
was then to introduce, uh,
然后介绍，呃，
the SQuAD vers- version 2 task.
SQuAD第2版任务。
And so many people felt that a defect of SQuAD version
而且很多人都觉得SQuAD版本存在缺陷
1 was that in all cases, questions had answers.
1在所有情况下，问题都有答案。
So, that you just had to find the answer in the paragraph,
那么，你只需要在段落中找到答案，
um, and so that's sort of turned into a kind of a ranking task.
嗯，这样就变成了一种排名任务。
You just had to work out what seems the most likely answer.
你只需要弄清楚最可能的答案。
I'll return that without really having
如果没有，我会回来的
any idea whether it was an answer to the question or not.
任何想法是否是问题的答案。
And so, for SQuAD version two,
因此，对于SQuAD第二版，
for the dev and test sets,
对于开发和测试集，
half of the questions have answers and half of
一半的问题有答案，有一半
the questions just don't have an answer in the passage,
这些问题在文章中没有答案，
um, it's slightly different distribution, the training data.
嗯，这是一个略有不同的分布，训练数据。
Um, and the way it works for scoring is the sort of, like,
嗯，它的评分方式就像是，
the no answer kind of counts as like one word as a sort of a special token.
无答案类似于一个单词作为一种特殊的标记。
So, if it's, if it should be a no answer and you say no answer,
所以，如果它是，如果它应该是一个没有答案，你说没有答案，
you get a score of one on the either exact match or the F-measure.
你在精确匹配或F测量得分为1。
And if you don't do that,
如果你不这样做，
you get a score of zero.
得分为零。
Um, and so, the simplest way of approaching SQuAD 2,0 would be to say, well,
嗯，接近SQuAD 2,0最简单的方法就是说，好吧，
rather than just always returning the best match in my system,
而不是总是在我的系统中返回最佳匹配，
I'll use some kind of threshold and only if the score is above a threshold,
我会使用某种阈值，只有当分数高于阈值时，
our counters and answer.
我们的柜台和答案。
You could do more sophisticated things.
你可以做更复杂的事情。
So another area that we've worked on quite a bit at Stanford is
所以我们在斯坦福大学工作的另一个领域是
this natural language inference task that I'll talk about later in the course.
这个自然语言推理任务，我将在后面的课程中讨论。
Um, but that's really about saying whether one piece of,
嗯，但这真的是说是否一件，
um, text is the conclusion of another,
嗯，文字是另一个的结论，
um, piece of text.
嗯，一块文字。
And so that's sort of a way that you can try and see whether, uh,
所以这是一种你可以尝试看看是否的方式，呃，
a piece of text actually gives you a justification and answer to what the question was.
实际上，一段文字可以为您提供理由并回答问题所在。
But at any rate, this trying to decide whether
但无论如何，这试图决定是否
you've actually got an answer or not is a quite difficult problem in many cases.
在很多情况下，你真的得到了答案是一个非常困难的问题。
So here's an example from SQuAD, um, 2,0.
所以这是SQuAD的一个例子，嗯，2,0。
So Genghis Khan united the Mongol and Turkic tribes of
所以成吉思汗联合了蒙古和突厥部落
the steppes and became Great Khan in 1206.
大草原在1206年成为大汗。
He and his successors expanded the Mongol Empire across Asia,
他和他的继任者扩大了整个亚洲的蒙古帝国，
blah, blah, blah, blah.
等等，等等，等等。
And the question is,
问题是，
when did Genghis Khan kill Great Khan?
成吉思汗何时杀死大汗？
And the answer to that is,
答案就是，
you know, uh, there isn't an answer because actually,
你知道，呃，没有答案，因为实际上，
Genghis Khan was a person named Great Khan and he didn't kill a Great Khan.
成吉思汗是一个名叫大汗的人，他并没有杀死一个大汗。
It's just not a question with an answer.
这不是一个问题的答案。
Um, but it's precisely what happens with systems is, you know,
嗯，但正是系统发生的事情是，你知道，
even though these systems get high scores in terms of points,
即使这些系统在积分方面得分很高，
they don't actually understand human language that well.
他们实际上并不了解人类语言。
So they look at something that says,
所以他们看的东西说，
when did Genghis Khan kill Great Khan?
成吉思汗何时杀死大汗？
Well, this is something that's looking for a date and there are
嗯，这是寻找约会的东西
some obvious dates in this passage there's 1206, 1234,
这篇文章中有一些明显的日期是1206,1234，
1251 and well, there's kill,
1251嗯，有杀，
and kill looks a little bit similar to destroyed.
和杀戮看起来有点类似于被摧毁。
I can see the word destroyed.
我看到这个词被毁了。
So that probably kind of matches.
所以这可能是一种匹配。
And then we're talking about, um,
然后我们谈论的，嗯，
Genghis Khan and there,
成吉思汗在那里，
I can see Genghis and Khan in this passage.
在这段经文中，我可以看到成吉思汗和汗。
And so it sort of puts that together and says
所以有点把它放在一起然后说
1234 is the answer when that isn't the answer at all.
当答案根本不是答案时，1234就是答案。
And that's actually kind of pretty typical of the behavior of these systems.
这实际上是这些系统行为的典型特征。
And so that, on the one hand, they work great.
因此，一方面，它们的工作效果很好。
On the other hand, they don't actually understand that much,
另一方面，他们实际上并没有那么了解，
and effectively asking whether there's,
并有效地询问是否存在，
this question is actually answered in the passage is a way of
这个问题实际上是在文章中回答的一种方式
revealing the extent to which these models
揭示这些模型的程度
do or don't understand what's actually going on.
做或不明白实际发生了什么。
Okay. So, at the time, um,
好的。所以，当时，嗯，
they built SQuAD version 2,0.
他们建立了SQuAD 2,0版。
They took some of, um,
他们拿了一些，嗯，
the existing SQuAD version one's systems,
现有的SQuAD版本系统，
and, um, modified them in a very simple way.
并且，嗯，以非常简单的方式修改它们。
I put in a threshold, um,
我提出了一个门槛，嗯，
score as to how good the final match was deemed to be,
评分最终比赛被认为有多好，
and said, Well, how well do you do on SQuAD 2,0?
并且说，你在SQuAD 2,0上的表现如何？
And the kind of systems that we saw doing well before,
我们之前看到的那种系统做得很好，
now didn't do that well,
现在做得不好，
so something like the BiDAF system that we mentioned before was now scoring about 62 F1,
所以像我们之前提到的BiDAF系统现在得分约为62 F1，
so that that was sort of hugely lowering
所以这有点大幅降低
its performance and reflecting the limits of understanding.
它的表现和反映了理解的极限。
Um, but it turned out actually that this problem didn't prove to
嗯，但事实证明这个问题并没有证明
be q- quite as difficult as the dataset authors,
是q-与数据集作者一样困难，
um, maybe thought either.
嗯，也许还在想。
Um, because it turns out that um,
嗯，因为事实证明，嗯，
here we are now in February 2019,
我们现在在2019年2月，
and if you look at the top of the leaderboard,
如果你看一下排行榜的顶部，
we're kind of getting close again to the point
我们有点接近这一点
where the best systems are almost as good as human beings.
最好的系统几乎和人类一样好。
So, um, the current top rate system there you can see is getting 87,6 F1,
所以，嗯，你可以看到目前的最高费率系统是87,6 F1，
which is less than two points behind where the human beings are.
这比人类落后不到两点。
Um, the SQuAD version 2 they also co- corrected the,
嗯，SQuAD版本2他们也共同纠正了，
um, scoring of human beings,
嗯，人类的得分，
so it's more of a fair evaluation this time, um,
所以这次更公平的评价，嗯，
so there's still a bit of a gap but, you know,
所以还有一点差距，但是，你知道，
the systems are actually doing, um, really well.
系统实际上正在做，嗯，非常好。
And the interesting thing there is,
而有趣的是，
you know, on the one hand these systems are impressively good.
你知道，一方面这些系统非常好。
Um, you can go on the SQuAD website and look
嗯，你可以去SQuAD网站看看
at the output of several of the good systems,
在几个好系统的输出，
and you can see that there are just a ton of things that they get right.
你可以看到他们做对的事情很多。
They're absolutely not bad systems.
他们绝对不是坏系统。
You have to be a good system to be getting five out of six of the questions right.
你必须成为一个好的系统，才能使六个问题中的五个正确。
Um, but, you know, on the other hand they still
嗯，但是，你知道，另一方面他们仍然
make quite elementary Natural Language Understanding Errors.
使相当基本的自然语言理解错误。
And so here's an example of one of those.
所以这是其中一个例子。
Okay, so this one,
好的，所以这个，
the Yuan dynasty is considered both a successor to
元朝被认为是两者的继承者
the Mongol Empire and an imperial Chinese dynasty.
蒙古帝国和中国的帝国王朝。
It was the khanate ruled by the successors of
这是由接班人统治的汗国
Mongke Khan after the division of the Mongol Empire.
蒙古帝国分裂后的蒙克汗。
In official Chinese histories the Yuan dynasty bore the Mandate of Heaven,
在中国官方历史中，元朝有天命，
following the Song dynasty and preceding the Ming dynasty.
继宋朝之后和明朝之前。
Okay. And then the question is,
好的。然后问题是，
what dynasty came before the Yuan?
元朝前来的是什么王朝？
And that's a pretty easy question,
这是一个非常简单的问题，
I'd hope, for a human being.
我希望，对于一个人来说。
Everyone can answer that question?
每个人都可以回答这个问题？
Okay, um, yeah, so it says in official Chinese histories Yuan Dynast- uh,
好的，恩，是的，所以在官方的中国历史上说，元代，
sorry the next sentence.
对不起下一句话。
Um, yeah followed- right the Yuan Dynasty following
嗯，是的，跟随着元朝
the Song dynasty and preceding the Ming dynasty.
宋朝和明朝之前。
But, you know actually um,
但是，你知道嗯，
this sort of the leading um,
这种领先的嗯，
Google BERT model says that it was the Ming dynasty that came before
谷歌BERT模型说明是以前的明朝
the Yuan Dynasty which you know is sort of elementarily
你知道的元朝是一种元素
wrong that reveals some of the same kind of it's
错了，揭示了一些同样的东西
not really understanding everything but it's doing a sort of a matching problem still.
没有真正了解一切，但它仍然在做一种匹配问题。
Okay. So, this SQuAD dataset has been useful and good.
好的。因此，这个SQuAD数据集非常有用。
It still has some major limitations and I just thought I'd
它仍有一些主要的局限性，我只是想到了
mentioned what a few of those are so you're aware of some of the issues.
提到了其中一些，所以你知道一些问题。
So one of them I've already mentioned, right,
所以其中一个我已经提过了，对，
that you're in this space where all answers are a span from the passage.
你在这个空间里所有的答案都是从这段经文开始的。
And that just limits the kind of questions you can
这只会限制你可以提出的问题
ask and the kind of difficult situations there can be.
问及可能存在的那种困难情况。
So, there can't be yes-no questions counting
所以，不能有 - 没有问题可数
questions or even any of the sort of more difficult implicit questions.
问题甚至是任何更困难的隐含问题。
So, if you think back to when you were in middle school and did reading comprehension,
所以，如果你回想起你在中学时的阅读理解，
I mean, it wasn't typically um,
我的意思是，它通常不是，
the case um, that you're being asked
你问的那个案子
questions that were just stated explicitly in the text of,
在文本中明确陈述的问题，
you know, Sue is visiting her mother in Miami.
你知道，苏正在迈阿密拜访她的母亲。
And the question was,
问题是，
who was visiting in Miami?
谁在迈阿密访问？
That wasn't the kind of questions you were asked you were normally asked questions um,
这不是你被问到通常被问到问题的问题，嗯，
like um, you know,
像嗯，你知道，
um, Sue is going to a job interview this morning,
嗯，苏今天早上要去面试，
um, it's a really important job interview for her future.
嗯，对她的未来来说，这是一次非常重要的面试。
At breakfast she um,
早餐时，她，嗯，
starts buttering both sides of her piece of toast um,
开始涂抹她吐司的两面，
and you are asked a question like, um,
并且你被问到一个类似的问题，嗯，
why um, is Sue buttering both sides of her piece of toast?
为什么，苏是在她的吐司的两面涂抹黄油？
And you're meant to be able to answer,
而你的意思是能够回答，
"She's distracted by her important job interview coming up later in the day."
“她在当天晚些时候接受的重要面试时会分心。”
Which isn't the- something that you can answer um,
哪个不是你可以回答的问题，
by just picking out a sub span.
通过挑选一个子跨度。
Um, a second problem which is sort of actually a bigger problem is um,
嗯，第二个问题实际上是一个更大的问题是嗯，
the way SQuAD was constructed for ease
SQuAD的构建方式是为了方便
and not to be too expensive and various other reasons was um,
而且不要太昂贵，还有其他各种原因，嗯，
paragraphs of Wikipedia were selected and then,
维基百科的段落被选中然后，
Mechanical Turkers were hired to say,
雇用机械车手说，
"Come up with some questions um,
“想出一些问题，嗯，
that can be answered by this this passage in version 1,1."
可以通过版本1,1中的这段文章来回答。“
And then in version two they were said- told,
然后在第二版他们被告知 -
"Also come up with some questions that
“还提出了一些问题
look like they're related to this passage but aren't actually answered in the passage."
看起来他们与这段经文有关，但实际上并没有回答这段经文。“
But, in all cases people were coming up with
但是，在所有情况下，人们都想出来
the questions staring at the passage and if you do that,
盯着文章的问题，如果你这样做，
it means that your questions are strongly
这意味着你的问题很强烈
overlapping with the passage both in terms of the,
与通道重叠，无论是
the words that are used and even the syntactic structures that are
使用的单词，甚至是句法结构
used for your questions tending to match the syntactic structures of the passage.
用于你的问题倾向于匹配文章的句法结构。
And so that makes question answering um, naturally easy.
所以这使问题回答嗯，自然很容易。
What happens in the real world,
在现实世界中会发生什么，
is this human beings think up questions and
这是人类想出的问题吗？
type something into a search engine and the way
在搜索引擎和方式中输入内容
that they type it in is completely distinct
他们输入它是完全不同的
from the way something might be worded on a website.
从网站上的措辞方式来看。
So that they might be saying something like,
所以他们可能会这样说，
you know, "In what year did the price of hard disks drop below a dollar a megabyte?"
你知道，“在哪一年，硬盘的价格降到一美元以下？”
Um, and the webpage will say something like
嗯，网页会说些什么
the cost of hard disks has being dropping for many years um,
硬盘的成本已经下降了很多年，
in I know whenever it was 2004 prices eventually crossed um,
我知道无论何时2004年的价格最终都超过了，
the dollar megabyte barrier or something like that.
美元兆字节的障碍或类似的东西。
But there's a quite different discussion of the ideas.
但是对这些想法的讨论却截然不同。
And that kinda matching is much harder and that's one of
那种匹配更难，而且是其中之一
the things that people have done other datasets have tried to do differently.
人们做过其他数据集的事情试图以不同的方式做。
Um, another limitation is that these questions and
嗯，另一个限制是这些问题和
answers are very much, find the sentence that's addressing the fact,
答案非常多，找到解决事实的句子，
match your question to the sentence,
将你的问题与句子相匹配，
return the right thing,
回归正确的事，
that there's nothing sort of more difficult than involves multi sentence,
没有什么比涉及多句更难的了，
combine facts together styles of inferencing,
将事实结合在一起的推理风格，
that the limits of cross sentence stuff there is pretty much limited to
那里的交叉句子的限制几乎是有限的
resolving co-reference which is something we'll talk about later in the class,
解决共同参考问题，这是我们将在课堂上讨论的内容，
that means that you see a he or she or an it,
这意味着你看到他或她或它，
and you can work out who that refers to earlier in the, this course.
你可以找出本课程前面提到的那些人。
Um, nevertheless, despite all those disadvantages,
嗯，尽管有这些缺点，
it sort of proved that SQuAD was, you know,
事实证明，SQuAD是，你知道，
well-targeted in terms of its level of difficulty, well-structured,
在困难程度，结构良好，目标明确，
clean dataset, and it's just been
干净的数据集，它就是这样
sort of everybody's favorite for a question answering dataset.
对于回答数据集的问题，每个人都很喜欢。
It also seems to have proved that actually for
它似乎也证明了其实
people who work in industry and want to build a question answering system,
在工业界工作并希望建立问答系统的人，
starting off by training a model in SQuAD,
从SQUAD培训模型开始，
actually turns out to work pretty well it turns out.
事实证明，事实证明它工作得很好。
I mean, it's not everything you want to do.
我的意思是，这不是你想做的一切。
You definitely wanna have relevant in domain data and be using that as well,
你肯定想要在域数据中有相关性并使用它，
but you know, it turns out that it seems to actually be a quite useful starting point.
但是你知道，事实证明它似乎是一个非常有用的起点。
Okay. So, what I wanted to show you now was a- is a concrete,
好的。那么，我现在想要告诉你的是一个具体的，
simple, neural question answering system.
简单的神经问答系统。
Um, and this is the model that was built by here and I guess she was
嗯，这是在这里建造的模型，我猜她是
sort of an Abby predecessor since she was the preceding head TA for CS 224N.
因为她是CS 224N的前任主管TA，所以有点像Abby的前任。
Um, so this system,
嗯，这个系统，
um, Stanford Attentive Reader it kind of gets called now.
嗯，Stanford Attentive Reader现在被称为。
I mean, this is sort of essentially
我的意思是，这有点基本上
the simplest neural question answering system that works pretty well.
最简单的神经问题回答系统，效果很好。
So, it's not a bad thing to have in mind as
因此，考虑到这一点并不是一件坏事
a baseline and it's not the current state of the art by any means.
一个基线，它不是任何方式的现有技术水平。
But you know, if you're sort of wondering what's the simplest thing that I can build
但是你知道，如果你想知道我能建立什么是最简单的事情
that basically works as a question answering system decently,
这基本上可以作为一个问题回答系统，
this is basically it.
这基本上就是这样。
Um, okay. So how does this work?
嗯，好的。那么这是如何工作的呢？
So the way it works is like this.
所以它的工作方式是这样的。
So, first of all,
所以，首先，
we have a question which team won Super Bowl 50?
我们有一个问题哪支球队赢得了超级碗50？
And what we're gonna wanna do is build a representation of a question as a vector.
而我们想要做的是建立一个问题的表示作为向量。
And the way we can do that is like this,
我们这样做的方式是这样的，
for each word in the question,
对于问题中的每个单词，
we look up a word embedding.
我们查找一个单词嵌入。
So, in particular it used GloVe- GloVe 300 dimensional word embeddings.
所以，特别是它使用了GloVe-GloVe 300维字嵌入。
Um, we then run an LSTM
嗯，我们然后运行LSTM
forward through the question and then kind of like Abby talked about,
通过问题前进然后有点像Abby谈到的，
we actually make it a bi-LSTM.
我们实际上把它变成了双LSTM。
So, we run a second LSTM backwards through the question.
因此，我们通过问题向后运行第二个LSTM。
And so then, we grab the end state of both LSTMs
然后，我们抓住两个LSTM的最终状态
and we simply concatenate them together into a vector of dimension 2D if,
如果，我们只是将它们连接成一个2D维度的向量，
if our hidden states of the LSTM are dimension
如果我们隐藏的LSTM状态是维度
d and we say that is the representation of the question.
d我们说这是问题的代表。
Okay. So, once we have that,
好的。所以，一旦我们拥有了，
we then start looking at the passage.
然后我们开始看这段话。
And so, for the start of dealing with the passage,
因此，对于处理该段落的开始，
we do the same thing.
我们做同样的事情。
We, um, look up a word vector for every word in
我们，嗯，查找每个单词的单词向量
the passage and we run a bidirectional LSTM,
通道，我们运行双向LSTM，
now being represented a bit more compactly um, across the passage.
在整个段落中，现在表现得更紧凑一点。
But then we have to do a little bit more work because we actually
但是我们必须做更多的工作，因为我们实际上
have to find the answer in the passage.
必须在文章中找到答案。
And so what we're gonna do is use
所以我们要做的就是使用
the question representation to sort of work out where the answer is using attention.
问题表示，以解决答案在哪里使用注意力。
So this is a different use of attention to machine translation.
所以这是对机器翻译的不同注意。
That kind of attention equations are still exactly the same.
那种注意方程式仍然完全相同。
But we've now got this sort of one question vector that we gonna be trying to
但是我们现在有了这样一个问题向量，我们将要尝试
match against to return the answer.
匹配以返回答案。
So, what we do is we, um,
所以，我们做的是我们，嗯，
work out an attention score between
计算出一个注意力得分
each word's bi-LSTM representation and the question.
每个单词的双LSTM表示和问题。
And so the way that's being done is we're using this bi-linear attention,
所以我们正在使用这种双线性关注，
um, that um, Abby briefly discussed and we'll see more of today.
嗯，那个，Abby简要讨论过，我们今天会看到更多。
We've got the question vector,
我们有问题向量，
the vector for a particular position in the passage
通道中特定位置的向量
to the two concatenated LSTM hidden states.
两个连接的LSTM隐藏状态。
So they're the same dimensionality.
所以它们是相同的维度。
We have this intervening learn W matrix.
我们有这个介入学习W矩阵。
So, we work out that quantity,
所以，我们计算出这个数量，
um, for each position,
嗯，对于每个职位，
and then we put that through a softmax which will give us
然后我们把它通过softmax给我们
probabilities over the different words in the passage.
对段落中不同词语的概率。
Um, and those give us,
嗯，那些给我们的，
um, our attention weights.
嗯，我们的注意力量。
And so at that point we have attention weights,
所以在这一点上我们有注意力量，
um, for different positions, um,
嗯，对于不同的职位，嗯，
in the passage and we just declare that,
在文章中，我们只是宣布，
um, that is where,
嗯，那就是，
um, the answer starts.
嗯，答案开始了。
Um, and then to get the end of the answer,
嗯，然后得到答案的结束，
we simply do exactly the same thing again apart from we train a different W matrix here,
除了我们在这里训练一个不同的W矩阵之外，我们再简单地做同样的事情，
and we have that,
我们有，
um, predict the end token.
嗯，预测结束标记。
And there's something a little bit subtle here.
这里有点微妙的东西。
Um, because, you know, really we're asking it to sort
嗯，因为，你知道，我们真的要求它排序
of predict the starts and the ends of the answer,
预测答案的开始和结束，
and you might think, but wait a minute.
你可能会想，但等一下。
Surely, we need to look at the middle of the answer as well because maybe the,
当然，我们也需要看看答案的中间部分，因为也许，
the most indicative words are actually going to be in the middle of the answer.
最具指示性的词实际上将在答案的中间。
Um, but, you know, really really what we're,
嗯，但是，你知道，我们真的是真的，
we're sort of implicitly telling the model of well,
我们有点含蓄地告诉模型，
when you're training, if there's stuff in the middle that's useful,
当你训练时，如果中间的东西有用，
it's the bi-LSTM's job to push it to the extremes of the span,
这是bi-LSTM的工作，将其推向极限，
so that this simple bi-linear attention
这样简单的双线性关注
will be able to get a big score at the start of the span.
将在跨度开始时获得一个大的分数。
And you might also think there's something
而且你可能也认为有些东西
funny that this equation and that equation are exactly the same.
有趣的是，这个等式和那个等式是完全一样的。
So, how come one of them is meant to know it's picking up beginning, um,
那么，他们中的其中一个是怎么意识到它正在开始，嗯，
and the other at the end?
而另一个在最后？
And again, you know, we're not doing anything to impose that.
而且，你知道，我们没有采取任何措施强加这一点。
We're just saying, neural network.
我们只是说，神经网络。
It is your job to learn.
这是你学习的工作。
Um, you have to learn a matrix here and a different one over there,
嗯，你必须在这里学习一个矩阵，在那里学习一个不同的矩阵，
so that one of them will pick out parts of the representation that
这样他们中的一个就会挑选出那些代表性的部分
indicate starts of answer spans and the other one ends of answer spans.
指示答案跨度的开始和答案跨度的另一端。
And so, that will then again pressure
然后，这将再次施加压力
the neural network to sort of self organize itself in
神经网络将自我组织起来
such a way that there'll be some parts of
这样的方式会有一些部分
this hidden representation that will be good at learning starts of spans.
这个隐藏的表示将擅长学习跨度的开始。
You know, maybe there'll be carried backwards by
你知道，也许会被倒退
the backwards LSTM and and some parts of it will be good at
向后的LSTM以及它的某些部分将擅长
learning where the spans end and then
学习跨度结束的地方
the W matrix will be able to pick out those parts of the representation.
W矩阵将能够挑选出表示的那些部分。
Um, but yeah, uh,
嗯，但是，呃，
that's the system. Um, yeah.
这就是系统。嗯，是的
So, um, so this is
所以，嗯，所以这是
the basic Stanford Attentive Reader model and it's just no more complex than that.
基本的Stanford Attentive Reader模型并没有比这更复杂。
Um, and the interesting thing is, you know,
嗯，有趣的是，你知道，
that very simple model actually works nicely well.
这个非常简单的模型实际上效果很好。
Um, so this is going back in time.
嗯，所以这可以追溯到时间。
Again, this was the February 2017 SQuAD version 1 leaderboard.
同样，这是2017年2月的SQuAD版本1排行榜。
Um, but at that time, that provide- like,
嗯，但那个时候，那个提供，像，
it always in neural networks quite a bit of your success
它总是在神经网络中相当于你的成功
is training your hyperparameters and optimizing your model really well.
正在训练你的超参数并真正优化你的模型。
And some time, you know,
有一段时间，你知道，
it's been repeatedly proven in neural network land that often you can get
它在神经网络领域被反复证明，通常你可以获得
much better scores than you would think from
比你想象的要好得多
very simple models if you optimize them really well.
非常简单的模型如果你真的很好地优化它们。
So there have been multiple cycles in sort of
所以有各种各样的循环
deep learning research where there
那里的深度学习研究
was a paper that did something and then the next person says,
是一篇论文做了什么然后下一个人说，
"Here's a more- more- more complex model that
“这是一个更复杂的模型
works better," and then someone else published a paper saying,
效果更好，“然后其他人发表了一篇论文说，
"Here's an even more complex than that model that works
“这比那个有效的模型更复杂
better," and then someone points out, "No.
更好，“然后有人指出，”没有。
If you go back to the first model and just really train its hyperparameters well,
如果你回到第一个模型并且真的很好地训练它的超参数，
you can beat both of those two models."
你可以击败这两种模式。“
And that was effectively the case about what
这实际上是关于什么的情况
was happening with the Stanford Attentive Reader.
斯坦福大学读者会发生这种情况。
That, you know, back in- back in February 2017,
你知道，2017年2月回来了，
if you just train this model really well,
如果你真的很好地训练这个模型，
it could actually outperform most of the early SQuAD systems.
它实际上可以胜过大多数早期的SQuAD系统。
I mean, in particular,
我的意思是，特别是
it could outperform, um, the BiDAF,
它可能胜过BiDAF，
the version of BiDAF that was around in early 2017 and,
2017年初出现的BiDAF版本，
you know, various of these other systems from other people.
你知道，其他人的其他各种系统。
But it was actually, at that time,
但实际上，当时，
it was pretty close to the best system that anyone had built.
它非常接近任何人建造的最佳系统。
Um, as I've already pointed out to you,
嗯，正如我已经向你指出的那样，
um, the numbers have gone up a lot since then.
嗯，从那时起，这些数字已经上升了很多。
So I'm not claiming that, um,
所以我没有声称，嗯，
this system is still as good as the best systems that you can build. But there you go.
这个系统仍然可以与您构建的最佳系统一样好。但是你去吧。
Um, so that's the simple system that already works pretty well,
嗯，这是一个已经很好用的简单系统，
but of course you want this system to work better.
但是你当然希望这个系统更好地工作。
Um, and so Danqi did quite a bit of work on that.
嗯，Danqi做了相当多的工作。
And so here I'll just mention a few things for, um,
所以我在这里只提几件事，嗯，
Stanford Attentive Reader++ as to
Stanford Attentive Reader ++ as
what kind of things can you do to make the model better.
你可以做些什么来改善模型。
And so here's a sort of a picture of, um,
所以这是一张照片，嗯，
the sort of the improved system and we'll go through
改进的系统，我们将经历
some of the differences and what makes it better.
一些差异以及使它变得更好的原因。
Um, there's something I didn't have before that I should just mention, right?
嗯，我之前没有的东西，我应该提一下，对吧？
Sort of this whole model, all the parameters of this model are just trained end to end,
整个模型的排序，这个模型的所有参数都是刚刚端到端的训练，
where your training objective is simply, um,
你的培训目标很简单，嗯，
working out how accurately you're predicting
弄清楚你预测的准确程度
the start position and how accurately you're predicting
起始位置以及您预测的准确程度
the end position so that the attention gives
结束位置，以便引起注意
you a probability distribution over start positions and end positions.
你在起始位置和结束位置的概率分布。
So you're just being asked what probability estimate
所以你只是被问到概率估算是多少
are you giving to the true start position and the true end position.
你是否给出了真正的起始位置和真正的终点位置？
And to the extent that though,
并且在某种程度上，
you know, those aren't one,
你知道，那些不是一个，
you've then got loss that is then being sort of summed in terms of log probability.
然后你就得到了损失，然后根据对数概率进行求和。
Okay. So how is this model, um,
好的。那么这个模型怎么样，嗯，
more complex now than what I showed before?
现在比我之前展示的更复杂？
Essentially in two main ways.
基本上有两种主要方式。
So the first one is looking at the question,
所以第一个是看问题，
we still run the BiLSTM as before.
我们仍然像以前一样运行BiLSTM。
Um, but now what we're going to do is it's a little bit crude
嗯，但现在我们要做的是它有点粗糙
just to take the end states of the LSTM and concatenate them together.
只是为了获取LSTM的最终状态并将它们连接在一起。
It turns out that you can do better by making use of all states in an LSTM.
事实证明，通过利用LSTM中的所有状态，您可以做得更好。
And this is true for most tasks where you
对于你来说，大多数任务都是如此
want some kind of sentence representation from a sequence model.
想要从序列模型中获得某种句子表示。
It turns out you can generally gain by using
事实证明，你通常可以通过使用获得
all of them rather than just the endpoints or that.
所有这些而不仅仅是端点或那些。
Um, so but this is just an interesting general thing to know again because, you know,
嗯，所以这只是一个有趣的一般事情再次知道，因为，你知道，
this is actually another variant of how that- how you can use attention.
这实际上是另一种变体 - 如何使用注意力。
There are, you know, a lot of sort of the last two years of neural NLP can be summed
你知道，有很多种神经NLP可以归结为最近两年
up as people have found a lot of clever ways to use
人们已经发现了许多聪明的使用方法
attention and that's been pairing just about all the advances.
注意力和所有的进步一直在配对。
Um, so what we wanna do is we want to have attention over the positions in this LSTM.
嗯，所以我们想做的是我们想要关注这个LSTM中的位置。
But, you know, this- we're processing the query first.
但是，你知道，我们首先处理查询。
So it sort of seems like we've got nothing to calculate attention with respect to.
所以我们似乎没有什么可以计算注意力的。
So what we do is we just invent something.
所以我们所做的就是发明一些东西。
So we just sort of invent.
所以我们只是发明。
Here is a vector and it's sometimes called a sentinel or some word like that,
这是一个向量，它有时被称为哨兵或类似的一些词，
but, you know, we just in our PyTorch say,
但是，你知道，我们只是在PyTorch中说，
"Here is a vector.
“这是一个载体。
Um, we're going to calculate, um,
嗯，我们要计算，嗯，
we initialize it randomly,
我们随机初始化它，
and we're gonna calculate attention with respect to that vector,
我们将计算关于该向量的注意力，
and we're going to use those attention scores, um, to, um,
我们将使用那些注意力分数，嗯，对，嗯，
work out where to pay attention, um,
找出要注意的地方，嗯，
in this BiLSTM, and then we just sort of train that vector so it gets values.
在这个BiLSTM中，然后我们只是训练该向量，以便获得值。
And so then we end up with a weighted sum of the time
因此，我们最终得到了时间的加权和
steps of that LSTM that uh, then form the question representation.
那个LSTM的步骤呃，然后形成问题表示。
Um, second change, uh,
嗯，第二次改变，呃，
the pictures only show a shallow BiLSTM but, you know,
图片只显示浅的BiLSTM，但是，你知道，
it turns out you can do better if you have a deep BiLSTM and say
事实证明，如果你有一个深刻的BiLSTM，你可以做得更好
use a three-layer deep BiLSTM rather than a single layer.
使用三层深BiLSTM而不是单层。
Okay. Then the other changes in
好的。然后其他的变化
the passage representations and this part arguably gets a little bit more hacky,
段落表示和这部分可以说有点多hacky，
um, but there are things that you can do that make the numbers go up, I guess.
嗯，但有些事情可以让你的数字上升，我想。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So- so firstly for the representation of words rather than only using
所以首先是表示单词而不是仅使用
the GloVe representation that the input vectors are
输入向量的GloVe表示
expanded so that- so a named entity recognizer and a part of speech tagger is run.
扩展，以便运行命名实体识别器和词性标记器。
And since those are sort of small sets of values,
因为这些是一些小的价值观，
that the output of those is just one-hot encoded and concatenated onto
那些输出只是一个热门编码并连接到
the word vector, so it represents if it's
单词矢量，所以它代表它是否
a location or a person name and whether it's a noun or a verb.
位置或人名，以及它是名词还是动词。
Um, word frequency proves to be a bit useful.
嗯，词频证明有点有用。
So there's your concatenating on sort of a representation of the word frequency as,
所以你的词汇频率表示为，
um, just sort of a float of the unigram probability.
嗯，只是unigram概率的浮点数。
Um, and then this part is kind of key to getting some further advances which is, well,
嗯，然后这部分是获得进一步发展的关键，这是，嗯，
it turns out that we can do a better job by doing some sort
事实证明，我们可以通过某种方式做得更好
of better understanding of the matching between the question and the passage.
更好地理解问题与段落之间的匹配。
And, um, this feature seems like it's
而且，嗯，这个功能看起来像是
very simple but turns out to actually give you quite a lot of value.
非常简单但事实证明实际上给了你很多价值。
So you're simply saying for each word in the question,
所以你只是对问题中的每个单词说，
uh, so for each word- well,  I said that wrong.
呃，所以对于每个字 - 好吧，我说错了。
For each word in the passage,
对于段落中的每个单词，
you were just saying, "Does this word appear in the question?"
你只是说，“这个词出现在问题中吗？”
And if so you're setting a one bit into
如果是这样的话，你就要设置一个
the input and that's done in three different ways: exact match,
输入和以三种不同的方式完成：完全匹配，
uncased match, and lemma match.
无限制的匹配和引理匹配。
So that means something like drive and driving, um,
所以这意味着驾驶和驾驶，嗯，
will match, and just that sort of
会匹配，就这样
indicator of here's where in the passage that's in the question.
这里的指标是问题所在段落中的位置。
In theory, the system should be able to work that out
理论上，系统应该能够解决这个问题
anyway that explicitly indicate and it gives quite a bit of value.
无论如何，它明确表明并且它给出了相当多的价值。
And then this last one does a sort of a softer version of that where it's using word
然后这最后一个做了一个更柔和的版本，它正在使用单词
embedding similarities to sort of calculate
嵌入相似性来计算
a kind of similarity between questions and answers,
问题和答案之间的一种相似性，
and that's a slightly complex equation that you can look up.
这是一个稍微复杂的等式，你可以查找。
But effectively, um, that you're getting the embedding of words and the question answers.
但实际上，嗯，你正在接受单词和问题答案的嵌入。
Each of those, you're running through a single hidden layer,
其中每一个，你都在通过一个隐藏层，
neural network, you know,
神经网络，你知道，
dot producting it, and then putting all that through a Softmax,
点击它产生它，然后通过Softmax将所有这些产品，
and that kind of gives you a sort of word similarity score and that helps as well.
这种类型给你一种单词相似度得分，这也有帮助。
Okay. So here's the kind of just overall picture this gives you.
好的。所以这是给你的整体画面。
So if you remember, um, um,
所以，如果你还记得，嗯，嗯，
there was the sort of the classical NLP
有那种经典的NLP
with logistic regression baseline, there's around 51.
使用逻辑回归基线，大约有51个。
So for sort of a fairly simple model,
所以对于一个相当简单的模型，
like the Stanford Attentive Reader,
像Stanford Attentive Reader，
it gives you an enormous boost in performance, right?
它会给你带来巨大的性能提升，对吧？
That's giving you close to 30 percent performance gain.
这样可以获得接近30％的性能提升。
And then, you know, from there,
然后，你知道，从那里，
people have kept on pushing up neural systems.
人们一直在推动神经系统。
But, you know, so this gives you kind of in some sense three quarters of
但是，你知道，所以这在某种意义上给你了四分之三
the value over the traditional NLP system and in the much more,
传统NLP系统的价值以及更多，
um, complex, um, neural systems that come after it.
嗯，复杂，嗯，它后面的神经系统。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
In terms of error reduction,
在减少错误方面，
they're huge but it's sort of more like they're giving you the sort of,
它们很大但有点像它们给你的那种，
um, 12 percent after that.
嗯，之后是12％。
Why did these systems work such a ton better um, than traditional systems?
为什么这些系统比传统系统工作得更好？
And so we actually did some error analysis of this and, you know,
所以我们实际上对此做了一些错误分析，你知道，
it turns out that most of their gains is because they can just do
事实证明，他们的大部分收益都是因为他们可以做到
better semantic matching of word similarities
单词相似度的语义匹配更好
or rephrasings that are semantically related but don't use the same words.
或与语义相关但不使用相同词语的改写。
So, to- to the extent that the question is where was Christopher Manning born?
那么，问题就在于克里斯托弗·曼宁出生的地方？
And the sentence says Christopher Manning was born in Australia,
句子说克里斯托弗曼宁出生在澳大利亚，
a traditional NLP system would get that right too.
传统的NLP系统也能做到这一点。
But that to the extent that you being able to get it right,
但是，只要你能够做到正确，
depends on being able to match,
取决于能够匹配，
sort of looser semantic matches so that we understand the sort of um,
一种更宽松的语义匹配，以便我们理解那种嗯，
you know, the place of birth has to be matching was born or something.
你知道，出生地必须匹配才能诞生或者什么。
That's where the neural systems actually do work much much better.
这就是神经系统实际上工作得更好的地方。
Okay. So, that's not the end of the story on question-answering systems.
好的。所以，这不是问答系统故事的结尾。
And I wanted to say just a little bit about um,
我想说一点关于嗯，
more complex systems to give you some idea um,
更复杂的系统给你一些想法嗯，
of what goes on after that.
之后发生了什么。
Um, but before I go further into that,
嗯，但在我进一步深入研究之前，
are there any questions on uh,
对呃有什么问题吗
up until now, Stanford Attentive Reader?
到目前为止，Stanford Attentive Reader？
[NOISE] Yeah.
[NOISE]是的
I have a question about attention in general.
一般来说，我有一个关于注意力的问题。
Every example we've seen has been just linear mapping with a weight matrix.
我们看到的每个例子都只是一个权重矩阵的线性映射。
Has anybody tried to convert that to a deep neural network and see what happens?
有没有人试图将其转换为深度神经网络，看看会发生什么？
Um, so yes they have.
嗯，是的，他们有。
Well, at least a shallow neural network.
好吧，至少是一个浅层的神经网络。
Um, I'll actually show an example of that in just a minute.
嗯，我实际上会在一分钟内展示一个例子。
So maybe I will um, save it till then.
所以也许我会，直到那时保存。
But yeah absolutely, um,
但是，是的，嗯，
yeah people have done that and that can be a good thing to um, play with.
是的，人们已经做到了，这对你来说是件好事，玩耍。
Anything else? Okay. Um, okay.
还要别的吗？好的。嗯，好的。
So, this is a picture of the BiDAF system,
那么，这是BiDAF系统的图片，
so this is the one from AI2 UDub.
所以这是来自AI2 UDub的那个。
And the BiDAF system is very well known.
BiDAF系统非常有名。
Um, it's another sort of classic version of
嗯，这是另一种经典版本
question-answering system that lots of people have used and built off.
许多人使用和建立的问答系统。
Um, and, you know,
嗯，你知道，
some of it isn't completely different to what we saw before but it has various additions.
其中一些与我们之前看到的并没有完全不同，但它有各种各样的补充。
So, there are word embeddings just like we had before,
所以，就像我们以前一样，有一些嵌入词，
there's a biLSTM running just like what we had before,
有一个像我们之前一样运行的biLSTM，
and that's being done for both the um,
那是为了嗯，
passage and the question.
通过和问题。
Um, but there are some different things that are happening as well.
嗯，但也有一些不同的事情正在发生。
So one of them is rather than just having word embeddings,
所以其中一个不仅仅是嵌入词，
it also processes the questions and passages at the character level.
它还处理角色级别的问题和段落。
And that's something that we're going to talk about coming up ahead in the class.
这就是我们将要讨论的在课堂上提前做的事情。
There's been a lot of work at doing character level processing in recent neural NLP,
在最近的神经NLP中进行角色级处理已经做了很多工作，
but I don't want to talk about that now.
但我现在不想谈论这个问题。
Um, the main technical innovation of the BiDAF model
嗯，BiDAF模型的主要技术创新
is this attention flow layout because that's in its name bidirectional attention flow.
是这种注意力流动布局，因为它的名称是双向关注流程。
And so, there was a model of attention flow where you have attention
因此，有一个注意力流动的模型，你需要注意
flowing in both directions between the query and the passage.
在查询和段落之间向两个方向流动。
And that was their main innovation and it was quite useful in their model.
这是他们的主要创新，在他们的模型中非常有用。
Um, but beyond that,
嗯，但除此之外，
there's you know, sort of more stuff to this model.
你知道吗，这个模型有更多的东西。
So after the attention flow layer there's again
所以在关注流层之后又有了
multiple layers of bidirectional LSTMs running.
运行多层双向LSTM。
And then on top of that their output layer is more
然后最重要的是他们的输出层更多
complex than the sort of simple attention version that I showed previously.
比我之前展示的那种简单的注意版复杂。
So let's just look at that in a bit more detail.
所以让我们再看一下细节。
Um so, for the attention flow layer.
嗯，对于注意力流层。
So, the motivation here was in the Stanford Attentive Reader,
所以，这里的动机是在Stanford Attentive Reader，
we used attention to map from
我们用注意力来映射
the representation of the question onto the words of the passage.
将问题表达在段落的文字上。
But, you know so as questions are whole mapping onto the words of the passage.
但是，你知道，因为问题完全映射到段落的文字。
Where their idea was well,
他们的想法很好，
presumably you could do better by mapping in both directions at the word level.
大概你可以通过在单词级别的两个方向上进行映射来做得更好。
So you should be sort of finding passage words that you can map onto question words,
所以你应该找到可以映射到问题单词的段落词，
and question words that you can map onto passage words.
并质疑你可以映射到段落词的单词。
And if you do that in both directions with attention flowing,
如果你在注意流动的两个方向上这样做，
and then run another round of sequence models on top of that,
然后再运行另一轮序列模型，
that you'll just be able to do much better matching between the two of them.
你可以在两者之间做更好的匹配。
And so the way they do that is, um,
他们这样做的方式是，嗯，
that they- they've got the bottom- so at
他们 - 他们已经到了底部 - 所以
the bottom layers they've sort of run these two LSTMs.
底层他们有点运行这两个LSTM。
So they have representations in the LSTM for each word and um,
所以他们在LSTM中为每个单词和嗯表示，
word and passage position.
词和通道的位置。
And at this point I have to put it in a slight apology because I just
在这一点上，我必须稍微道歉，因为我只是
stole the equations and so the letters that are used change.
偷走了方程式，因此使用的字母发生了变化。
Sorry. But, so these are the um,
抱歉。但是，这些是嗯，
question individual words and these are the passage individual words.
质疑单个词，这些是个别词的段落。
And so, what they're then wanting to do is to say for each passage word,
所以，他们当时想要做的就是对每个段落来说，
and each question word, I want to work out a similarity score.
和每个问题词，我想得出相似性得分。
And the way they work out that similarity score is they build a big concatenated vector.
他们计算相似性得分的方式是他们建立一个大的连接向量。
So there's the LSTM representation of the passage word, the question word,
所以有通道词的LSTM表示，问题词，
and then they throw in a third thing where they do a Hadamard product,
然后他们投入第三件事，他们做了Hadamard产品，
so an element-wise product of the question word and the context word.
所以问题词和上下文词的元素方面的产物。
Um, you know, for a neural net purist, throwing in
嗯，你知道，对于一个神经网络纯粹主义者，投掷
these kind of Hadamard products is a little bit of a cheat because
这种Hadamard产品有点像作弊因为
you kind of would hope that a neural net might just learn that
你会希望神经网络能够学到这一点
this relation between the passage and the question was useful to look at.
这段经文和问题之间的关系很有用。
But you can find a lot of models that put in
但你可以找到许多投入的模型
these kind of Hadamard product because it's sort of
这种Hadamard产品因为它的种类
a very easy way of sort of having a model that knows that matching is a good idea.
一种非常简单的方法，让模型知道匹配是一个好主意。
Because essentially this is sort of looking for each question and passage word pair.
因为基本上这是寻找每个问题和通道词对。
You know, do the vectors look similar in various dimensions?
你知道，矢量在各个方面看起来相似吗？
You can sort of access very well from looking at that Hadamard product.
通过查看Hadamard产品，您可以很好地访问。
So that- so you take that big vector,
那么 - 所以你拿那个大矢量，
and you then dot-product that with a learned weight matrix,
然后你用学到的权重矩阵点积，
and that gives you a similarity score
这会给你一个相似度
between each position in the question and the context.
在问题中的每个位置和上下文之间。
And so then what you're gonna do is use that to
那么你要做的就是用它来做
define attentions that go in both directions. Um-
定义两个方向的注意力。 UM-
So for the, um, context,
所以，对于，嗯，上下文，
the question attention, this one's completely straightforward.
关注的问题，这一点完全是直截了当的。
So, you put these similarity scores through a soft-max.
所以，你通过soft-max来表示这些相似性得分。
So for each of the i positions in the passage or sort of,
因此，对于通道中的每个位置或类型，
having a softmax which is giving you a probability distribution,
有一个softmax给你一个概率分布，
over question words and then you're coming up with
在问题的话，然后你想出来
a new representation of the i-th position which is then the attention weighted,
第i个位置的新表示，然后是注意力加权，
um, version, the attention weighted average of those question words.
嗯，版本，那些问题词的注意加权平均值。
Um, so you're sort of,
嗯，所以你有点儿，
having attention weighted view of the question mapped onto each position in the passage.
具有注意力加权视图的问题映射到段落中的每个位置。
Um, you then want to do something in the reverse direction.
嗯，你想要反向做点什么。
Um, but the one in the reverse direction is done subtly differently.
嗯，但反方向的那个巧妙地区别对待。
So you're again starting off, um,
所以你再次开始，嗯，
with the- the same similarity scores but this time they're sort of wanting to, sort of,
与相同的相似度得分，但这次他们有点想要，有点，
really assign which position,
真的指定哪个位置，
in which position in the question is the one that's, sort of,
在问题中的哪个位置是那个，有点像，
aligning the most so that they're finding a max and so that they're finding
最对齐，以便他们找到最大值，以便他们找到
which is the most aligned one and so then for each of,
哪个是最对齐的，所以每个，
for each of the i's,
对于我的每一个，
they're finding the most aligned question word.
他们找到了最对齐的问题词。
And so then they're doing a softmax over these m scores and then those are being
然后，他们在这些m分数上做了一个softmax，然后就是那些
used to form a new representation of the passage by,
用于形成通道的新表示，
sort of, summing over these attention weights.
对这些注意力进行总结。
Okay. So you build these things up and this then
好的。所以你建立这些东西然后呢
gives you a new representation where you have,
给你一个新的代表，你有，
um, your original representations of the passage words.
嗯，你对段落词的原始陈述。
You'd have a new representation that you've built from
您将拥有一个新的表示形式
this bidirectional attention flow and you
这种双向关注流程和你一样
look at these sort of Hadamard products of them and
看看他们和他们的这些Hadamard产品
that then gives you kind of the output of the BiDAF layer and that output of
然后，它会为您提供BiDAF层的输出和输出
the BiDAF layer is then what's sort of being fed as
那么BiDAF层就像被喂食一样
the input into these nick- next sequence of LSTM layers.
输入到这些缺口的LSTM层序列中。
Okay. Um, and so yeah,
好的。嗯，是的，是的，
um, so then that's the modeling layer.
嗯，那就是建模层。
You have another two BiLSTM layers and so the way they do the,
你有另外两个BiLSTM层，所以他们的方式，
um, suspense selection is a bit more complex as well.
嗯，悬疑选择也有点复杂。
Um, so that they're then, um,
嗯，这样他们就这样，嗯，
sort of taking the output of the modeling layer and putting it through a sort of
获取建模图层的输出并将其放入某种类型
a dense feed-forward neural network layer and then softmaxing over that,
一个密集的前馈神经网络层然后softmaxing，
um, and that's then getting a distribution of
嗯，那就是分发了
a start and you're running yet another LSTM kind of a distribution finish.
一个开始，你正在运行另一个LSTM类型的分发完成。
Um, yeah. So, that gives you some idea of a more complex model.
嗯，是的因此，这可以让您了解更复杂的模型。
Um, you know, in some sense,
嗯，你知道，从某种意义上说，
um, the summary if you go further forward than here is that, sort of,
嗯，如果你比这里更进一步的总结是那样的，
most of the work in the last couple of years,
过去几年的大部分工作，
people have been producing progressively more complex architectures with
人们一直在逐步生产更复杂的架构
lots of variants of attention and effectively that has been giving good gains.
许多变化的注意力和有效的，已经取得了很好的收益。
Um, I think I'll skip since time is running,
嗯，我想我会跳过时间，
out, showing you that one.
出来，给你看一个。
But, um, let me just mention this FusionNet model
但是，嗯，让我提一下这个FusionNet模型
which was done by people at Microsoft because this relates to the answer,
这是由微软的人做的，因为这与答案有关，
the attention question, right?
关注的问题，对吧？
So p- so people have definitely used different versions of attention, right?
所以p-所以人们肯定会使用不同版本的注意力，对吗？
So that in some of the stuff that we've shown we tend to emphasize
因此，在我们展示的一些内容中，我们倾向于强调
this bi-linear attention where you've got two vectors mediated by a matrix.
这种双线性关注，你有两个由矩阵介导的向量。
And I guess traditionally at Stanford NLP,
我猜传统上在斯坦福NLP，
we've liked this, um,
我们喜欢这个，嗯，
version of attention since it seems to very directly learn
版本的关注，因为它似乎非常直接的学习
a similarity but other people have used a little neural net.
相似但其他人使用了一点神经网络。
So this is, sort of, a shallow neural net to
所以这就是一种浅层的神经网络
work out attention scores and there's, sort of,
得出注意力得分，有，有点，
no reason why you couldn't say, maybe it would be even better if I
没理由你不能说，如果我可能会更好
make that a deep neural net and add another layer.
使那个深度神经网络并添加另一层。
Um, and some of, you know,
嗯，还有一些，你知道，
to be perfectly honest, um,
说实话，嗯，
some of the results that have been done by people including Google
包括谷歌在内的人已经完成了一些结果
argue that actually that NLP version of attention is better.
认为实际上NLP版本的注意力更好。
Um, so there's something to explore in that direction.
嗯，所以有朝这个方向探索的东西。
But actually, um, the people in FusionNet didn't head that direction because they said,
但实际上，嗯，FusionNet的人没有朝那个方向前进，因为他们说，
"Look, we want to use tons and tons of attention.
“看，我们想要使用吨和吨的注意力。
So we want an attention computation that's pretty
所以我们想要一个非常好的注意力计算
efficient and so it's bad news if you have to
高效，所以如果你不得不这样做是坏消息
be evaluating a little dense neural net at
正在评估一个小密集的神经网络
every position every time that you do attention."
每次你注意的每一个位置。“
So this bi-linear form is fairly appealing
所以这种双线性形式非常吸引人
but they then did some playing with it so rather than having a W matrix
但是他们接着做了一些游戏而不是W矩阵
you can reduce the rank and complexity of
你可以降低等级和复杂性
your W matrix by dividing it into the product of two lower rank matrices.
你的W矩阵除以两个低阶矩阵的乘积。
So you can have a U and a V matrix.
所以你可以有一个U和V矩阵。
And if you make these rectangular matrices that are kind of skinny,
如果你制作这些细长的矩形矩阵，
you can then have a sort of a lower rank factorization and,
然后你可以有一种较低等级的因子分解，
that seems a good idea.
这似乎是一个好主意。
And then they thought well,
然后他们心想，
maybe really you want your attention distribution to be symmetric.
也许你真的希望你的注意力分布是对称的。
So we can actually put in the middle here,
所以我们实际上可以放在这里，
we can have the U and the V, so to speak,
我们可以拥有U和V，可以这么说
be the same and just have a diagonal matrix in
是相同的，只有一个对角矩阵
the middle and that might be a useful way to think of it.
中间，这可能是一个有用的方式来思考它。
And that all makes sense from linear algebra terms but then they thought,
从线性代数术语来看，这一切都是有道理的，但他们认为，
"Oh, non-linearity is really good in deep learning.
“哦，非线性在深度学习中确实很好。
So why don't we, sort of,
那么我们为什么不这样呢？
stick the left and right half through a ReLU and maybe that will help.
通过ReLU坚持左右两半，也许这会有所帮助。
[LAUGHTER] Which doesn't so much make sense in your linear algebra terms, um,
[笑声]你的线性代数术语中没有那么有意义，嗯，
but that's actually what they ended up using as their, um, attention forms.
但这实际上是他们最终用作他们的注意形式。
There are lots of things you can play with when doing your final project.
在做最后的项目时，你可以玩很多东西。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
And, but, you know, their argument is still, you know,
而且，但是，你知道，他们的论点仍然是，你知道，
that doing attention this way is actually much much
以这种方式注意实际上是非常多的
cheaper and so they can use a lot of attention.
更便宜，所以他们可以使用很多的关注。
And so they build this very complex tons of attention model, um,
所以他们建立了这个非常复杂的注意力模型，嗯，
which I'm not going to try and explain, um,
我不打算试着解释一下，嗯，
all of now, um,
现在，嗯，
but I will show you this picture.
但我会告诉你这张照片。
Um, so a point that they make is that a lot of
嗯，他们提出的一点是很多
the different models that people have explored in different years you,
人们在不同年代探索过的不同模型，
that, you know, they're sort of,
那，你知道，他们有点像，
doing different kinds of attention.
做不同的关注。
That you could be doing attention right,
你可以正确地关注，
lining up with the original LSTM,
排队原始LSTM，
you could run both sides through some stuff and do attention,
你可以通过一些东西跑两边并注意，
you can do self attention inside your layer that there are a lot of
你可以在你的层内自我关注，有很多
different attentions that different models have explored.
不同模型探索过的不同注意事项。
And essentially what they are wanting to say is,
基本上他们想说的是，
let's do all of those and let's make it deep and do it all
让我们做所有这些，让我们深入并做到这一切
five times and the numbers will go up. And to some extent the answer is,
五次，数字会上升。在某种程度上答案是，
yeah they do and the model ends up scoring very well.
是的，他们这样做，模特最终得分很好。
Okay, um, so the one last thing I just wanted to mention but not explain is,
好的，嗯，所以最后一件我想提的但不解释的是，
I mean in the last year there's then been
我的意思是去年那时候
a further revolution in how well people can do these tasks.
人们如何完成这些任务的进一步革命。
And so people have developed algorithms which produce contextual word representation.
因此人们开发了产生上下文单词表示的算法。
So that means that rather than a traditional word vector,
这意味着，而不是传统的单词向量，
you have a representation for each word in a particular context.
您可以在特定上下文中对每个单词进行表示。
So here's the word frog in this particular context and the way people build
所以这里有关于这个特定背景中的青蛙这个词以及人们建立的方式
those representations is using something
那些陈述正在使用某些东西
like a language modeling tasks like Abby talked about,
像Abby谈到的语言建模任务，
of saying putting probabilities of words in
说词的概率
context to learn a context-specific word representation.
上下文以学习特定于上下文的单词表示。
And ELMo was the first well-known such model.
ELMo是第一个这样着名的模型。
And then people from Google came up with BERT,
然后谷歌的人想出了BERT，
which worked even better.
哪个工作得更好。
Um, and so BERT is really in some sense is
嗯，所以BERT在某种意义上确实是
super complex attention Architecture doing a language modeling like objective.
超级复杂的注意力架构做一个像客观的语言建模。
We're going to talk about these later, um,
我们稍后会讨论这些，嗯，
I'm not going to talk about them now, um,
我现在不打算谈论他们，嗯，
but if you look at the current SQuAD 2,0 Leaderboard,
但如果你看看当前的SQuAD 2,0排行榜，
um, you will quickly,
嗯，你会很快，
um - sorry that's- oh I put the wrong slide and that was the bottom of the leaderboard.
嗯 - 对不起 - 哦，我放了错误的幻灯片，这是排行榜的底部。
Oops, slipped at the last minute.
哎呀，在最后一分钟滑倒了。
If you go back to my slide which had the top of the leaderboard, um,
如果你回到我的幻灯片，它有排行榜的顶部，嗯，
you will have noticed that the top of the leaderboard,
你会注意到排行榜的顶部，
every single one of the top systems uses BERT.
每个顶级系统都使用BERT。
So that's something that you may want to
这就是你可能想要的东西
consider but you may want to consider how you could
考虑但你可能想考虑如何
use it as a sub-module which you could add other stuff too as many of these systems do.
使用它作为子模块，您可以添加其他东西，就像许多这些系统一样。
Okay. Done for today.
好的。今天完成了。